[音乐响起--字幕精校中--By Persisan]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: All right.
这是CS50。
This is CS50.
到此为止。
And this is the end.
剩下的实际上就是您的最终项目。
All that remains here on out is really your final projects.
我们迫不及待想看到您创建的内容。
And we cannot wait to see what you create.
今天，我们认为我们会做的是回顾一下，
Today what we thought we would do is take a bit of a look back,
但我们也很期待，以便您确切地知道
but also we'll look forward so that you know exactly where
以及CS50本身以外的其他功能。
and what you can do beyond CS50 itself.
但是首先要感谢。
But first a word of thanks.
我们当然在勒布戏剧中心
We are, of course, here in the Loeb Drama Center
与《美国话剧团》合作
with The American Repertory Theater, who have been our amazing hosts
这整个学期。
this whole semester.
的确，他们呼吸了新的生活，新的灯光，新的动画，新的声音
And truly, they have breathed new life, new lights, new animation, new sounds
进入CS50。
into CS50.
我们非常感激能有这样的特权
And we are so grateful to have had such a privilege
与这里的才华横溢的团队合作，确实带来了
to work with the amazingly talented team here to indeed bring
整个生命阶段，并在整个学期中逐步发展。
this whole stage to life and evolve it over the course of the semester.
当然，还有CS50的团队。
And then, of course, there's CS50'S team.
虽然我是舞台上唯一的一个
And though I'm the only one here on stage
这个学期其他人分散得很远，
with everyone else spread quite far apart this semester,
没有CS50的团队，我们就拥有了我们拥有的视频，
it would not be without CS50's team that we have the videos that we have,
我们拥有的技术以及所有视觉效果
the technology that we have, and all of the visuals
希望补充一下您自己拥有的一切
that supplement, hopefully, everything that you yourselves
一直在动手。
have been doing hands on.
因此，非常感谢两个团队使本学期成为可能。
So thank you truly to both teams for having made this semester all possible.
可以说，在更加不寻常和困难的时期中，这些就足够了。
These are suffice it to say, among the more unusual and difficult times.
我们希望，如果您现在正在观看直播，或者从现在开始的某个时间，
And we hope, if you're watching this now live, or in some time from now,
这样可以使每个人都身体健康。
that this finds everyone healthy and well.
的确，我们已经帮助您找到了自己的出路
And that, indeed, we have helped you find your way
沿着这条学习新事物的道路前进。
along this path of learning something new.
当然，还有更多的人
Of course, there's more folks even than that
在幕后，CS50的整个团队。
behind the scenes, CS50'S whole team.
当我看着这里的人群时，真的，那里
And when I look out on the crowd here, really, there
没有人在这里。
is no crowd here in person.
如果您想知道幕后的样子，
And if you've wondered what it looks like behind the scenes,
这张照片是什么的照片
pictured here is a photograph of exactly what
我正在看到我们何时举行这些课程中的每一个。
it is I am seeing when we hold each of these classes.
确实，如果我们进行放大，那么当我们进行这些对话时
And indeed, if we Zoom in, when we're having these conversations
或回答或问问题，这真的只是我们
or answering or asking questions, it really is just us
和今年的一些电视屏幕。
and some TV screens here this year.
但是，我们确实希望不久以后能团聚。
But we do look forward to all reuniting before long.
现在幕后，确实有整个团队。
Now behind the scenes, there's indeed this whole team.
实际上，这里的图片只是其中的大部分，甚至没有
In fact, pictured here are just most of, but not even
所有，CS50的教学人员，助教和课程助手，
all, CS50'S teaching Fellows, teaching assistants, and course assistants,
无论是在哈佛还是在耶鲁，没有他们，这个学期也不会
both at Harvard and at Yale, without whom this semester would also not
可能的。
be possible.
因为它们确实是支撑结构的支柱和支撑结构
Because they are, indeed, the backbone of and the support structure
让每个人最终完成
for getting everyone ultimately to the finish
与问题集，实验室等保持一致。
line with problem sets, labs, and more.
但值得注意的是，我们所有人都容易犯错误。
But it's worth noting that we are all fallible.
而且，的确，我被告知这在什么时候具有启发性
And, indeed, I'm told it's fairly instructive when
我做错了什么，或者在舞台上有些困惑
I do something completely wrong, or get a little befuddled here on stage
并且无法弄清楚为什么我自己的代码无法正常工作，
and can't quite figure out why my own code isn't working,
还是不能完全回答我的问题。
or can't quite answer a question off the top of my head.
这一切当然发生在我们所有人身上。
This all happens, certainly, to all of us.
因此，即使您在这里感觉到最后
So even if you are feeling here, toward the end
在学期中，并不是所有事物都被点击了
of the semester, that not everything quite clicked
而且有时您仍在努力在代码中找到该错误，
and you're still struggling sometimes to find that bug in your code,
还是您仍在搜寻或寻找一些较小的答案
or you're still googling or searching for some answer to some smaller
技术问题，请放心，或者在了解情况时感到放心，
technical problem, rest assured, or take comfort in knowing,
那永远不会消失。
that that is never really going to go away.
实际上，除了所有错误之外，还要加强这一点
And in fact, to reinforce that, besides all of the mistakes
我在这里做了舞台，我们以为我们会分享一些片段，
I here have made on stage, we thought we would share a little bit of a clip,
如果您愿意的话，从几周前教员准备时开始
some bloopers if you will, from when the teaching staff some weeks ago prepared
在视频上传递TCP / IP数据包的效果非常好，
that passing of TCP/IP packets on video, which worked out wonderfully well,
人们在上，下，左，右走过的地方。
where folks were passing up, down, left and right.
目的是获得三个TCP / IP数据包
The goal of which was to get three TCP/IP packets
从Zoom的右下角开始
from the bottom right-hand corner of Zoom
缩放的左上角。
to the top left-hand corner of Zoom.
但是我们认为我们可以让您一窥到底发生了什么
But we thought we would give you a glimpse of what actually went on
在幕后，花了多少时间才带走了我们
behind the scenes and just how many takes it took us
甚至使演示正确。
to get even that demonstration right.
我给您一些CS50的团队。
I give you some of CS50'S team.
[视频回放]
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
-我们去。
- There we go.
缓冲。
Buffering.
好的。
OK.
乔希？
Josh?
- 你好。
- Hi.
-海伦，哦！
- Helen, oh!
[笑声]
[LAUGHTER]
-[听不清]。
- [INAUDIBLE].
不，等等
No, wait.
太好了，乔希。
That was amazing, Josh.
嗯，索菲？
Um, Sophie?
[笑声]
[LAUGHTER]
惊人的。
Amazing.
那太完美了。
That was perfect.
莫妮
Moni?
[笑声]
[LAUGHTER]
我想我 -
I think I--
-[听不清]。
- [INAUDIBLE].
- 惊人的。
- Amazing.
-家伙？
- Guy?
那太精彩了。
That was amazing.
谢谢你们。
Thank you all.
- 超好的！
- So good!
[掌声]
[APPLAUSE]
[结束播放]
[END PLAYBACK]
DAVID MALAN：可以这么说，计算机科学对我们所有人来说都很困难。
DAVID MALAN: So suffice it to say, computer science is hard for all of us.
因此，有些感觉，一些挫败感
And so some of these feelings, some of these frustrations
永远不会消失。
are never going to go away.
但希望您确实拥有工具包中的所有其他工具，
But hopefully you have, indeed, all the more tools in your toolkit,
现在更多的基础可以建立
all the more of a foundation now to build on
这样您就可以在向前迈进时感到不舒服
so that you can take comfort in being a little uncomfortable as you forge ahead
并解决新问题，学习新语言，
and solve new problems, learn new languages,
并最终获得新的想法和技能。
and ultimately pick up new ideas and skills.
但是请记住，仅对于CS50，最终会发生什么
But remember, for CS50 alone, what ultimately
在这门课程中重要的不是什么
matters in this course is not so much where
你最终会和你的同学有关，但是你最终会在哪里
you end up relative to your classmates, but where you end
开始时相对于您自己。
up relative to yourself when you began.
考虑一下，这不是很早以前就开始的。
And consider, it wasn't all that long ago that you began.
实际上，也许在几周前，
In fact, just some weeks ago was this perhaps,
您在CS50中遇到的最大问题，只是尝试
the biggest of your problems in CS50, just trying
弄清楚如何使金字塔正确对齐，
to figure out how to get the pyramid to align right,
不管您使用的是舒适度较低的版本还是更多
whether you did the less comfortable version or the more
舒适的版本，弄清楚如何打印空间，
comfortable version, figuring out how to print spaces,
如何将金字塔等移开，弄清楚如何嵌套循环，
how to shift the pyramid over and the like, figuring out how to nest loops,
更不用说正确处理所有分号和编译步骤了。
let alone getting all of the semicolons and compilation steps right.
然后，快进一两周前
And then, fast forward to just a week or two ago
当您构建自己的Web应用程序时，
when you built your very own web application, one
使用第三方API并提取了几乎实时的数据
that used a third party API and pulled in nearly real time data
并为用户生成视图，并有一个控制器来控制
and generated views for the user, had a controller governing
与模型完全一样，您正在读取和写入的所有数据
with the model exactly all of the data you were reading and writing
等等。
and the like.
就像，这是过去几个月的巨大方法。
Like, that is a huge way to have gone over the course of just a few months.
因此，也要对此感到安慰。
So take comfort in that, too.
尤其是当您进入最终项目时
Especially as you dive into your final project
可能还会撞到更多的墙
and might bump up against some more walls, those, too,
您最终会完成吗？
will you ultimately push through.
那么，在本学期的课程中，我们专注于什么？
So what have we focused on over the course of this semester?
很多时候我们都花时间谈论和进行编程。
A lot of the times we've spent time talking about and doing programming.
但实际上，我们想认为这是更高层次的
But really, we'd like to think it's some of the higher level
想法和外卖是最后的你
ideas and the takeaways that are what last you
远远长于这些语言的细节。
far longer than the particulars of these languages.
无论是Scratch还是C，Python，JavaScript或SQL，
Whether it's Scratch or C or Python or JavaScript or SQL,
或我们研究过的任何其他实用工具，所有这些
or any of the other practical tools that we looked at, all of those
最终会以某种形式过时。
are eventually in some form going to be out of date.
否则他们可能会留在我们这里，是较老的语言
Or they might remain with us is older languages,
但是会出现更新更好的事情。
but newer and better things will come along.
那么，我们希望在过去的几个月中，
And what we hope, then, is that over the past few months,
您已经摆脱了基础知识和诸如此类的基础
you've walked away with the fundamentals and sort of a foundation on which you
可以引导自己学习新事物，因为它们会不断涌现
can bootstrap yourself to learn new things as they come out
并真正将新事物减少到其基本组成部分，
and really reduce new things to their basic building blocks,
我们开始的拼图，您从中获得的第一原则
the puzzle pieces with which we began, first principles from which you
可以推断出一些新系统，新硬件的方式，
can infer how some new system, some new piece of hardware,
某种新语言必须如何工作。
how some new language must surely work.
因为在引擎盖下，到最后还是要这样，
Because underneath the hood, at the end of the day, it's still going to be,
在一段时间内，只有0和1。
for some time, just 0's and 1's.
因此，我们在第0周介绍了回忆，计算思维，
And so we introduced in Week 0, recall, computational thinking,
鼓励您更系统，更算法地思考。
encouraging you to think more methodically, more algorithmically.
但是实际上，计算思维只是计算机科学家的化身
But really, computational thinking is just a computer scientist's incarnation
我们可能认为只是批判性思维的东西。
of what we might otherwise think of as just critical thinking.
该过程作为输入信息
This process is taking as input information
并产生一些解决方案。
and producing as output some solution.
在这两者之间，当然是我们的算法，
And in between there, of course, are our algorithms, the black box that's
做一些有趣的事情，也许很难。但是最终
doing something interesting and perhaps difficult. But at the end of the day,
这是解决问题的方法。
this is problem solving.
不管使用哪种语言，这都行不通
And this isn't going anywhere, irrespective of the languages
您在使用过程中使用或拿起甚至忘记的地方。
that you use or pick up or even forget somewhere along the way.
的确，今天，无论是输入还是输出都是二进制形式，
And indeed, today, too, whether this is input and output in binary form,
或仅仅是信息和决定或事实和结论，
or it's just information and decisions or facts and conclusions,
输入和生产的过程
this process of taking input and producing
作为输出正确答案，正确结论，
as output correct answers, correct conclusions,
正确的决定有望与您同在
correct decisions is hopefully going to be with you far
比C或Python的详细信息长
longer than the particulars of C or Python
或我们在本学期中花费了更多的动手技能。
or any of the more hands-on skills that we've spent time on this term.
还记得，至少在CS50中，
And recall, too, that at least within CS50,
我们建议您使用的工具评估方法的质量
the tools with which we propose that you evaluate the quality of your approach
解决问题的方法是这三个轴，第一个也是最重要的
to problem solving are these three axes, the first and foremost
其中肯定是正确的。
of which is surely correctness.
因为如果它不起作用，那么这首先意味着什么？
Because if it doesn't work, what's the point of it all in the first place?
因此，从输入到输出获取代码，算法和过程
So getting your code, your algorithm, your process from input to output
正确无疑是最重要的。
to be correct is certainly paramount.
但是，随之而来的是设计问题。
But after that comes questions of design.
如果您确实想构建更复杂的系统，
If you actually want to build more complex systems,
或解决更复杂的问题，您真的
or solve more sophisticated problems, you really
确实希望为这些问题设计干净的解决方案。
do want to design your solutions to those problems cleanly.
您不希望它们变慢或效率低下。
You don't want them to be slow or inefficient.
您不希望它们实际造成混乱。
You don't want them to be a mess in real terms.
您不希望您的代码是完全无法理解的。
You don't want your code to be completely undecipherable.
因为这只会妨碍您长期使用这些相同的工具，
Because that's just going to hamper you longer term to using those same tools,
那些相同的库来解决更有趣的事情，
those same libraries to solve more interesting,
更复杂的问题。
more sophisticated problems.
而且肯定会增加接口的难度
And it's surely going to make it harder to interface
与其他人，其他协作者和其他系统。
with other people, other collaborators, and other systems.
确实，按照这些思路，风格仍然重要吗？
And indeed along those lines, is style still important?
对于我们来说，这可能是三重奏中的第三次了。
It's perhaps the third in this trio for us.
但这是代码的美感，以及变量的缩进
But it's the aesthetics of your code, and the indentation in the variables
所有这些，就像您可能用我们的人类语言传达的那样，
and all that, much like you might convey in our human language,
标点符号之类的东西使您的脚步向前。
put your best foot forward with punctuation and the like.
它只会帮助其他人了解您。
It just helps other people understand you.
实际上，即使我们花费了大量时间进行互动
And indeed, even though we spent a lot of our time interacting
在一天的结束过程中，通过计算机进行类似的操作，
with computers, in a course like this, at the end of the day,
你真的只是在交流。
you're really just communicating.
无论您是要与机器还是与其他人交流，
And whether you're communicating to a machine or to another human,
干净利落地以有助于您的想法的方式进行操作，
doing that cleanly and in a way that helps your ideas,
您采用的解决方案肯定同样重要
your solutions, become adopted is surely no less important
比其他一些想法要好。
than some of these other ideas as well.
但是其他基本构件呢？
But what about other basic building blocks
超越了我们所做的特定语言和片段？
that transcend the particular languages and pieces that we did?
好吧，抽象，这个采用相当复杂的想法的想法
Well, abstraction, this idea of taking fairly complicated ideas
并简化它们，因此您不必担心较低的级别
and simplifying them so you don't have to worry about the lower level
实施细节，您只能专注于解决方案
implementation details, you can focus only on the solution
该拼图或该构建块实际提供的内容。
that that puzzle piece or that building block actually provides.
抽象无处不在。
And abstraction is everywhere around us.
当然，在代码中，我们将get_string之类的功能视为一种抽象。
Certainly in code, we saw functions like get_string as an abstraction.
我不知道。
I don't know.
我真的不记得确切的get_string
I don't really remember exactly how get_string
在引擎盖下实现，更不用说功能了
is implemented underneath the hood, let alone a function
C附带的功能，例如printf。
that comes with C, like printf.
但我知道它有效。
But I know that it works.
而且我知道这需要输入。
And I know that it takes input.
我知道它会产生输出。
I know that it produces output.
因此，我可以建立自己的想法，自己的软件，
And I can therefore build my own ideas, my own software,
在该构建块的顶部，抽象出这些细节。
on top of that building block, abstracting away those particulars.
在现实世界中，我们也将事物抽象化-
And in the real world, too, we abstract things--
我们始终采用复杂的想法或流程来抽象事物
we abstract away things all of the time, taking a complex idea or a process
并假设可以做到。
and assume that that will be done.
可能有人这样做。
Someone else might do that.
因此，我可以基于该过程的输出，
And I can therefore build on the output of that process,
即使我自己也不是基础实施方面的专家
even if I am myself am no expert in the underlying implementation
细节。
details thereof.
但是，还有一个精确度，另一个想法
But then there's precision, this other idea
非常重要的地方，当然在编写代码时，
where it's super important, certainly when writing code,
而且当与另一个人交谈时，要精确并清楚地说明
but also when talking to another human, to be precise and make super clear
你是什么意思。
what you mean.
并考虑极端情况，考虑输入
And to consider the corner cases, to consider the inputs
您可能不会期望的，但仍然可能
that you might not otherwise expect, but might nonetheless
发生，以便您不会犯错，并有一些意外的行为，因为我们
happen so that you don't err and have some unexpected behavior, as we
当然在实际代码中做过不止一次。
certainly did more than once in actual code.
有时，抽象和精度
And sometimes, abstractions and precisions
彼此有点矛盾。
are kind of at odds with one another.
因为抽象会让您想一想
Because abstraction would sort of have you think at
并在相当高的水平上交谈，而精确
and talk at a fairly high level, whereas precision
会建议你真的应该进入杂草
would suggest that you really should get into the weeds
真的要一步一步地去给某人
and really go step by step by step when it comes to giving someone
其他或计算机指令。
else or a computer instructions.
而且我们认为我们可以将其变为现实，
And we thought we would bring this to life, perhaps,
举几个例子。
with a couple of examples.
我们认为我们会尽力让尽可能多的人参与进来，
And we thought we would try to involve as many people as we can in this,
尽管很远，但如果可以的话，请所有人参加，
albeit from afar, by having everyone, if you can,
拿出一张纸和一支钢笔或一支铅笔。
take out a piece of paper and a pen or pencil.
如果您还没有足够的可用的话，也可以。
It's OK if you don't quite have that available.
如果您愿意，也可以在计算机上执行此操作
You can do this on a computer, too, if you'd rather
在记事本或平板电脑上画画，或类似的东西都可以。
draw on a notepad or a tablet, or something like that totally fine.
但理想情况下，现在取出要绘画的东西和一些东西
But ideally, taking out now something with which to draw and something
依靠。
to draw on.
我们将继续尝试并应用一些原则
We're going to go ahead and try to apply some principles
计算思维，看看有多有用或有多伤害
of computational thinking and see just how helpful or hurtful
它是在一个或另一个级别上使用抽象或精度。
it is to use abstraction or precision at one level or another.
所以我想做到这一点，布莱恩，我们将需要
So I think to do this, Brian, we're going to need
观众的帮助。
a helping hand from the audience.
我认为我们需要一个人
I think we're going to need for one person
到外面去自愿写口头指示
out there to volunteer to write instructions verbally
给其他人。
for everyone else.
我们将对待观众中的每个人，
We're going to treat everyone in the audience,
或实际上，听众中的n减去1个人
or really, n minus 1 people in the audience
就像今天将要编程的计算机一样。
as the computers today who are going to be programmed.
我们需要一名人类志愿者来当程序员。
And we need one human volunteer to be the programmer.
那位程序员将是Daniel。
And that programmer is going to be Daniel.
Daniel，谢谢您的自愿。
So Daniel, thank you for volunteering.
布赖恩，我们可以继续与丹尼尔分享，只有丹尼尔，
Brian, could we go ahead and share with Daniel, and only Daniel,
我们希望其他人画的东西的图片？
a picture of something that we want everyone else to draw?
Daniel，您稍后应该在屏幕上看到的内容，
So Daniel, what you should see on your screen in a moment,
如果还没有的话，是一张照片。
if you haven't already, is a picture.
不要告诉别人这是什么。
Don't tell anyone else what it is.
您可以随时使用任何单词。
You may use any words in a moment that you want.
请勿使用双手或类似手势。
You should not use your hands or any gestures like that.
但是目标是口头写一个算法
But the goal is going to be to write an algorithm verbally
对于房间中的其他每个人，一步一步地，
for everyone else in the room, step by step,
因此理想情况下他们会画出您所看到的内容。
so that ideally they draw what it is you see.
您可以说任何您想说的，但不能说任何肢体动作。
And you can say anything you want, but just no physical gestures.
那有意义吗？
Does that make sense?
- 知道了。
- Got it.
你想谈谈你自己吗
And do you want to say a little bit about yourself
在开始之前先进入小组？
first to the group before we begin?
学生：好的。
STUDENT: Sure.
我叫丹尼尔。
My name's Daniel.
我来自耶鲁大学Ezra Stiles College。
I'm from Ezra Stiles College at Yale University.
这个学期我真的是CS50。
And I really CS50 this semester.
大卫·马兰：哦，太好了。
DAVID MALAN: Oh, wonderful.
感谢您的志愿服务。
Thank you for volunteering.
让我们继续前进，让其他人拥有他们的论文
And let's go ahead and have everyone else with their paper
和铅笔或钢笔准备好了。
and pencil or pen ready.
丹尼尔（Daniel），每个人要做的第一件事就是第一步。
Daniel, what should be the first thing everyone does, step one.
学生：好的。
STUDENT: OK.
因此，我们要绘制的第一件事是六角形。
So the first thing we're going to draw is a hexagon.
因此，它是规则的六边形。
So it's a regular hexagon.
并且我们将确保绘制它，以便其中一个顶点
And we're going to make sure that we draw it so that one of the vertices
在六边形的最底部，并且其中一个顶点
is on the very bottom of the hexagon, and one of the vertices
在六边形的顶部。
is at the very top of the hexagon.
因此，一侧没有平放。
So one side is not laying flat.
你正在做的 -
You're doing--
大卫·马兰：哇，该死，该死。
DAVID MALAN: Wup, dut, dut dut.
没有手势。
No hand gestures.
学生：没有手，没有手。
STUDENT: No hands, no hands.
正确的。
Right.
一个顶点在最顶部，一个顶点在最底部。
One vertice at the very top, one vertice is at the very bottom.
而且您的侧面还有其他四个顶点。
And you've got your other four vertices on the sides.
所以一旦有了六角形，下一步
So once you've got your hexagon, your next step
将会找到您的六边形的中点。
is going to be find your midpoint of the hexagon.
因此，一旦找到中点，您就可以
And so once you've found your midpoint, you're
从顶点到该中点画三条线。
going to draw three lines from a vertices to that midpoint.
您要选择绘制的顶点
The vertices that you're going to choose to draw from
从最底端到中点，然后从中点到顶点
are the very bottom to the midpoint and then from the midpoint to the vertices
在顶部顶点的左侧和右侧。
that are on the left and right of the top vertices.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: All right.
还有任何最终指示吗？
Any final instructions?
学生：我认为，应该是这样。
STUDENT: I think, hopefully, that should be it.
大卫·马兰：[音频不清晰]。
DAVID MALAN: [INAUDIBLE].
这些是很长的第一步和第二步。
Those were very long steps one and two.
但是，是的。
But yes.
好吧，让我们继续揭示一下。
All right, well, let's go ahead and reveal.
这将是一点点黑客。
This will be a little bit of a hack.
但是，如果有人，每个人都乐于接受
But if anyone everyone is comfortable picking up
他们的纸或平板电脑，并握住它
their piece of paper or their tablet and holding it
在他们的Zoom相机前稳稳地摆放5或10秒，
in front of their Zoom camera steadily for five or 10 seconds,
我们将确切地看到每个人都画了什么。
we'll see exactly what everyone has drawn.
如果进入图库视图，您将可以看到其他所有人。
If you go into gallery view, you'll be able to see everyone else.
丹尼尔，希望您能看到一些熟悉的图片？
Daniel, hopefully you're seeing some familiar pictures?
我认为我们一定有范围。
I think we definitely have range.
您是否看到一个或多个与您的想法相符的东西？
Are you seeing one or more that match what you had in mind?
学生：是的。
STUDENT: Yeah.
它们看起来都不错。
They all look pretty good.
戴维·马兰：所有人？
DAVID MALAN: They all?
好吧，很好。
All right, so good.
那么，让我继续，然后在屏幕上分享
Let me go ahead, then, and share on my screen
丹尼尔刚才描述了什么。
in just a moment what it is Daniel was describing.
因此，布莱恩事先与丹尼尔分享的是这张照片
So what Brian had shared with Daniel in advance was this picture
在这里，我敢说是一个立方体。
here, which I dare say is a cube.
但实际上，它是由一个六边形然后是附加的线组成的
But indeed, it's composed of a hexagon and then the additional lines
丹尼尔描述的。
that Daniel described.
丹尼尔（Daniel），我确实碰巧看到了，也许是在《缩放》的第二页和第三页上
And Daniel, I did happen to see, maybe on pages two and three of the Zoom
窗口中，肯定有一些不完全是立方体。
window, there were definitely some that weren't quite cubes.
您如何对待自己的想法
What was going through your mind as to how you approached
您提供的算法？
the algorithm that you provided?
学生：我想-
STUDENT: I wanted to--
对我来说，穿过我的头的第一件事是一个立方体。
to me, the first thing that went through my head was a cube.
但是我知道有很多方法可以绘制一个立方体。
But I knew that there's so many ways to draw a cube.
我不想将其描述为一个多维数据集。
I didn't want to describe it as a cube.
因为如果我说只是画一个立方体，我知道
Because if I said just draw a cube, I knew
我们会得到很多不同的结果。
that we would get tons of different results.
所以我想尽可能清楚。
So I wanted to be as clear as possible.
我知道，如果我可以用某种数学方式来描述它，
And I knew that if I could describe it in sort of a mathematical way,
用六角形描述它并描述它
describing it with a hexagon and describing it
顶点在中点，希望会有更多的人
with the vertices in the midpoint, that hopefully more people would
能够绘制精确的形状。
be able to draw a precise shape.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
说的真好。
Really well said.
现在，如果我们每个人的音量都很大，那么奇怪的是，
Now if we had everyone's volume on, odd are,
您现在可能会听到一些咯咯的笑声，
you'd hear a bit of chuckling now, perhaps,
或有点尴尬。
or maybe a little bit of awkwardness.
我敢说并不是所有的照片都是那样的，
And I daresay not all of the pictures quite turned out that way,
但这是一个完美的例子，说明抽象也许可以帮助我们
but that's a perfect example of where maybe abstractions can kind of get us
陷入麻烦。
into trouble.
因为如果丹尼尔刚才说的，画一个立方体，对，你们中的一些人
Because if Daniel had just said, draw a cube, right, some of you
可能会立即开始绘制一个立方体。
might start drawing immediately a cube.
但是你们中的许多人都会有一个问题，那么方向应该是什么？
But many of you would have a question, well, what should the orientation be?
大小应该是多少？
What should the size be?
职位应该是什么？
What should the position be?
因此，精确度变得越来越重要。
And so there, precision becomes increasingly important.
但越精确，你们中的几率就越大
But the more precise it gets, odds are some of you
只是数量的细节和某种迷失的方向不知所措
just kind of got overwhelmed with the amount of detail and sort of lost track
你的笔或铅笔应该在某一点
where your pen or pencil was supposed to be at one point
因为您的工作水平要低得多。
because you were operating at a much lower level.
那么，就有这种紧张感了。
So there's this tension, then.
但是我认为我们确实使你们中的一些人达到了终点线。
But I think we did get some of you to that finish line.
让我们看看我们现在是否无法减轻所有人的压力，
Let's see if we can't now take the pressure off of all of you,
并特别感谢Daniel，让我们
and thank you to Daniel, in particular, let's
看看我们现在是否不能让你们所有人一起编程给我，如果可以的话。
see if we can't now have all of you collectively program me, if you will.
所以我要继续在这里拉起我的屏幕
So I'm going to go ahead and pull up my screen here
在这里，我可以在屏幕上用鼠标和光标进行绘制。
where I have the ability to draw with my mouse and cursor on my screen here.
而Brian，如果您不介意，可以与所有人分享
And Brian, if you don't mind, could you share with everyone
否则，我保证我不会提前看过的照片。
else a picture that I promise I have not seen in advance.
因此，我们将看到情况如何。
So we will see how this goes.
所以我是Zoom室中唯一的一个
So I'm the only one right now in the Zoom room
尚未看到这张照片。
that has not seen this picture.
但是Brian离开了，只向所有人提供了URL。
But Brian has gone and provided only you all with the URL.
因此，将其拉到屏幕上。
So pull that up on your screen.
然后，布莱恩，如果我们可以反复呼吁一些志愿者的话。
And then, Brian, if we could perhaps iteratively call on some volunteers.
我为什么不尝试一步一步地画出别人告诉我的事情？
Why don't I try to draw what people tell me to do, step by step?
布莱恩·于：好的。
BRIAN YU: All right.
大卫没有看到这一点。
David has not seen this.
我只是在五分钟前选择了这个。
I just picked this out, like, five minutes ago.
如果你想给他举手，所有人都会举手，例如，
And you're all going to raise your hand if you want to give him, like,
下一步操作的一条指令。
one instruction for what to do next.
让我们从乔治开始。
And let's start with George.
学生：所以您将从绘画开始
STUDENT: So you're going to start by drawing
屏幕顶部附近的圆圈。
a circle near the top of the screen.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: OK.
屏幕顶部附近的圆圈。
A circle near the top of the screen.
让我说清楚，我在计算机上没有删除功能。
And let me make clear, I have no delete abilities on the computer.
所以一旦我提交，我们就进入了。
So once I commit, we're in.
因此，在屏幕顶部附近画一个圆。
So drawing a circle near the top of the screen.
好的。
OK.
谢谢你，乔治。
Thank you, George.
Brian，第二步？
Brian, step two?
布莱恩·于：好，接下来我们去索菲亚。
BRIAN YU: All right, let's go to Sophia next.
学生：然后，在屏幕的正中央，用黑色圆圈填充门，
STUDENT: Then, in the very center of the screen, door a black, filled in circle,
这大约是顶部圆圈的十分之一。
which is approximately a tenth of the size of the circle at the top.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: OK.
我听说一个黑色的实心圆圈是大小的十分之一。
A black, filled in circle, I heard, that's a tenth of the size.
因此，我将要做类似的事情，然后将其阴影化。
So I'm going to do something like this, and then just kind of shade it in.
好的，谢谢索菲亚。
All right, thank you, Sophia.
第三步？
Step three?
布莱恩·于：我们去圣地亚哥。
BRIAN YU: Let's go to Santiago.
学生：您将再画一个圆。
STUDENT: You're going to draw another circle.
但这实际上不是一个圆圈，
But it's not actually going to be a circle,
它更像是一个椭圆，它将比第一个更大。
it's more of an ellipse, that's going to be bigger than the first one.
所以它将在中间。
So it's going to be in the middle.
并将其围成一个圆圈
And it's going to enclose that filled in circle
并在底部留一些空间。
and leave some room in the bottom.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: OK.
所以这是一个椭圆形。
So it's an ellipse.
它比第一个圆圈大。
It's bigger than the first circle.
但是它包围着较小的那个吗？
But it encloses the smaller one?
好吧，所以我听到了这样的话。
All right, so I heard kind of this.
好的。
OK.
第4步？
Step 4?
学生：在那个较小的椭圆下，
STUDENT: Under that smaller ellipse, you're
想要在其下画一个更大的圆圈
going to want to draw a bigger circle underneath it
并表现得好像圆正穿过那个椭圆，
and act as if the circle is going through that ellipse,
但实际上不显示穿过椭圆的线。
but don't actually show the lines going through the ellipse.
也就是说，我们在下面画了一个更大的圆圈，但没有
So that is, we draw a bigger circle underneath, but without having
线通过。
the lines go through.
看起来它似乎正在经历其边缘。
It looks like it will kind of be going through the edge of it.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: OK.
我在这里有点担心，但是我听到的是这样的，也许是吗？
I'm a little worried here, but what I heard was like this, maybe?
第五步？
Step five?
布莱恩·于（Brian Yu）：好的，接下来我们转到[音频不清晰]。
BRIAN YU: All right, let's go to [INAUDIBLE] next.
学生：所以在这种中椭圆形中，
STUDENT: So in that kind of middle ellipse,
你知道，例如当孩子表现得像飞机一样时，
you know, like, when kids act like they're an airplane,
然后他们发出飞机噪音，
and then they make, like, airplane noise,
然后他们用胳膊做那奇怪的事情？
then they do that weird thing with their arms?
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：恩。
DAVID MALAN: Uh huh.
学生：所以在那中间的椭圆形上画些像手臂一样的东西，
STUDENT: So draw those kind of, like, arms in that middle ellipse,
从大椭圆形出来。
coming out of the big middle ellipse.
戴维·马兰（DAVID MALAN）：在椭圆的中间吗？
DAVID MALAN: In the middle ellipse?
这个低一点？
This lower one?
学生：外面的那个。
STUDENT: The one outside of it.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：哦，这个大椭圆形？
DAVID MALAN: Oh, this big ellipse?
学生：是的，外在的界限。
STUDENT: Yeah, the outer bound.
是的。
Yeah.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：好的，所以我应该像小孩子一样举起手来-
DAVID MALAN: All right, so I should draw some hands like a kid would have when--
好的。
OK.
我不确定这会顺利结束。
I'm not sure this is going to end well.
布莱恩·于：好的。
BRIAN YU: All right.
我们需要更多的志愿者来帮助David完成这项工作。
We need some more volunteers to help David finish this.
让我们去加布里埃尔。
Let's go to Gabrielle.
学生：好的。
STUDENT: OK.
尝试画一个-
Try to draw a--
大卫·马兰（DAVID MALAN）：尝试是有效的词。
DAVID MALAN: Try is the operative word.
[笑声]
[LAUGHTER]
学生：您有一个更大的椭圆
STUDENT: You've got a bigger ellipse that's
在最底部，它比顶部和中部都大，
at the very bottom, that's bigger than both the top and middle one,
但中间的那条和那一条之间没有重叠的线
but showing no overlapping lines between the middle one and the one
您正在尝试。
that you're trying.
戴维·马兰（DAVID MALAN）：所以不要显示重叠的线。
DAVID MALAN: So show no overlapping lines.
因此，我听到了更大的椭圆。
So I heard an even bigger ellipse.
因此，抱歉，对不起。
So, like, oops, sorry.
这？
This?
好的？
OK?
学生：干得好。
STUDENT: Good job.
戴维·马兰：谢谢。
DAVID MALAN: Thank you.
好的。
OK.
Good.
保持积极的援军到来。
Keep the positive reinforcement coming.
最后几步？
Final couple steps?
布莱恩·于：好的。
BRIAN YU: All right.
[？伊卡？]
[? Ika? ?]
学生：您还必须执行另一步骤
STUDENT: One other step you would have to do
画一个小圆圈，比那个小
is draw a small, filled in circle, slightly smaller than the one
你已经画过了，就在第一个圆的中心
you already drew, right in the center of the first circle
你在顶部画了。
you drew right at the top.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: OK.
就在第一个圆的中心。
Right in the center of the first circle.
好的。
OK.
我认为这对我来说已经初具规模。
And I think this is starting to take shape for me.
我为我之前的一些决定感到遗憾。
And I regret some of my earlier decisions.
布莱恩·于：[音频不清晰]，您想提供额外的说明吗？
BRIAN YU: [INAUDIBLE],, you want to provide an additional instruction?
学生：您刚刚绘制的最后一个圆圈之间的另一个圆圈
STUDENT: Another circle in between the last one you just drew
在圆的边缘之间，所以
and in between the edge of the circle, so
在该圆的左侧，您将绘制另一个圆。
to the left of that circle you're going to draw another circle.
戴维·马兰（DAVID MALAN）：在这个圆圈的左边？
DAVID MALAN: To the left of this circle?
学生：嗯。
STUDENT: Mhm.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: OK.
布莱恩·于：还有瑞安？
BRIAN YU: And Ryan?
学生：在下面，您将要重复相同的过程，
STUDENT: Underneath, you're going to want to repeat the same process,
除了在右侧画一个圆。
except draw a circle on the right side.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: OK.
小循环。
Little loop.
布莱恩·于：我想我们可能还要再走一两个步骤。
BRIAN YU: I think we've got maybe one or two more steps left.
让我们回到索菲亚。
Let's go back to Sophia.
学生：在实心圆圈下方，即椭圆的中间，
STUDENT: Underneath the filled in circle, that's in the middle ellipse,
您想绘制该圆的两个副本
you want to draw two replicas of that circle
在原始椭圆的下方。
below the original one in the middle ellipse.
戴维·马兰（DAVID MALAN）：在椭圆的中间，所以在这里。
DAVID MALAN: In the middle ellipse, so here, OK.
我想我知道这是什么。
I think I know what this is.
布莱恩·于：杰森，最后一条指令怎么样？
BRIAN YU: And Jason, how about one last instruction?
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: All right.
学生：在最上方的圆圈下方，
STUDENT: Underneath, in the top most circle,
在三下，因此排成三个圆圈，画一个宽V，
under the three, so the row of three circles, draw a wide V,
有两条直线的形状。
sort of shaped with two straight lines.
DAVID MALAN：宽V带两条直线。
DAVID MALAN: A wide V with two straight lines.
好的。
OK.
我认为那部分我被钉住了。
That part, I think, I nailed.
我可以切换显示吗？
Shall I switch over and reveal?
因此，这是我相信所有人都给的URL。
So this is the URL I believe all of you were given.
我还没去过
I have not visited it yet.
但是，如果我现在去参观。
But if I go and visit this now.
嘿，那还不算太糟。
Hey, that's not all that bad.
好吧，我绝对是绕道而行。
All right, I definitely took a detour partway through.
但这是另一个例子。
But here's another example.
您是否刚开始按如下方式绘制雪人，例如，
Had you just started with draw a snowman as follows, like,
确实可以帮助我使自己的精神定位相似
that might have helped orient me, truthfully, similar in spirit
但以丹尼尔（Daniel）的设计为例，它将为您提供有关我的思想模型
to Daniel's design that would have given you a mental model of what I,
或给我一个我应该一直在画的心智模型。
or given me a mental model of what it is I should have been drawing.
因此，在这里，抽象也很难。
So here, too, abstraction is hard.
甚至精度也很难确定正确的细节水平
And even precision is hard and figuring out the right level of detail
操作是解决问题过程的一部分。
to operate at is kind of part of the process of problem solving.
不过，现在看来，这还算不错。
Though, now that I look at it, that's actually not half bad.
就像，我肯定在这里做错了。
Like, I definitely did the wrong thing over here.
但是对我们所有的在线志愿者都做得很好。
But very well done to all of our volunteers online.
因此，当您
So remember these kinds of details when you're
当你给某人某事时，试图向某人解释一些过程
trying to explain some process to someone, when you're giving someone
说明，即使是在现实世界中，
instructions, even if it's for something mundane in the real world,
就像去办事或在市场上取货一样，要精确
like going to run errands or pick up supplies at the market, being precise
当然很重要，但是您提供的精度越高，就越容易
is certainly important, but the more precision you provide, the much easier
这是一个人迷失在那些杂草中。
it is for the person to get lost in those weeds.
因此，有时某个人可能需要的只是更高级别的详细信息列表。
And so sometimes a higher level list of details is all that someone might need.
因此，您现在具备了编程和做事的能力
So now that you have this ability to program and to do things
我们已经在讲座和习题集中向您展示了
that we've shown you in lectures and problem sets,
确实有能力找出
and indeed, have the ability to figure out
如何做我们甚至还没有向您展示的事情，
how to do things that we haven't even shown you,
我们想花点时间考虑一下您是否应该做这些事情
we wanted to take a moment to consider just whether you should do those things
以及，如果应该的话，应该如何做。
and, if you should, how you should do them.
但是，您不仅可以凭自己的直觉回答这些问题，
But beyond just answering these questions with your own instincts,
我们认为我们会邀请一些同事
we thought we would invite some of our colleagues
由哲学系提出一个更正式的框架，
from the Philosophy department to propose a more formal framework,
一个思考过程，通过它我们可以解决问题
a thought process by which we can approach problems
在技术和代码编写方面
when it comes to technology and the writing of code
最终只是因为我可以编写一些东西来帮助我们做出决定，
to help us decide, ultimately, just because I can code something,
我应该，如果确实如此，我应该怎么做？
should I, and if so, indeed, how should I do that?
因此，请允许我介绍一下Meica哲学系的同事
So allow me to introduce our colleagues from the Philosophy department, Meica
Magnani和Susan Kennedy。
Magnani and also Susan Kennedy.
梅卡（Meica）？
Meica?
MEICA MAGNANI：嗨。
MEICA MAGNANI: So hi.
我是Meica Magnani。
I'm Meica Magnani.
我是嵌入式道德计划的哲学博士后
I am a philosophy postdoc with the Embedded Ethics Program
在哈佛。
here at Harvard.
苏珊·肯尼迪：你好。
SUSAN KENNEDY: Hi.
我是Susan Kennedy。
I'm Susan Kennedy.
我还是哈佛大学嵌入式道德计划的哲学博士后。
And I'm also a philosophy postdoc with the Embedded Ethics Program at Harvard.
MEICA MAGNANI：在我们开始之前，
MEICA MAGNANI: And before we get started,
我只想谈谈嵌入式道德计划。
I'll just say a few things about the Embedded Ethics Program.
所以我们是哲学家和计算机的跨学科团队
So we are an interdisciplinary team of philosophers and computer
科学家们共同努力，将伦理学纳入计算机科学
scientists working together to integrate ethics into the computer science
课程。
curriculum.
这种方法背后的想法是嵌入道德推理工具
The idea behind this approach is to embed tools of ethical reasoning
自己进入计算机科学课程。
into computer science courses themselves.
这样做的原因是，在对设计，部署进行决策时，
The reason for this is that when making decisions about the design, deployment,
或一项技术的发展，无论是否意识到，
or development of a piece of technology, one is, whether or not one realizes it,
做出符合道德的决定。
making ethical decisions.
也就是说，做出具有社会，政治，
That is, making decisions which stand to have social, political,
或人类的影响。
or human impact.
在哈佛，我们认为这对计算机科学家很重要
At Harvard, we think it's important for computer scientists
配备用于思考这些影响的工具。
to be equipped with tools for thinking through these implications.
苏珊·肯尼迪（SUSAN KENNEDY）：技术对我们拥有强大的力量和影响力。
SUSAN KENNEDY: Technology holds a lot of power and influence over us.
从广义上讲，这意味着设计技术的人员也可以这样做。
And that means, by extension, that the people who design technology do, too.
现在，您开始考虑什么职责
Now that you're starting to think about what responsibilities
您可能是计算机科学家，所以您
you might have as computer scientists, so you
可以避免明显的不幸事故，例如面部混搭，
can avoid notable mishaps, like face mash, for instance,
我们将把您的注意力转向社交媒体平台的主题
we're going to turn your attention to the topic of social media platforms
以及它们如何影响和参与的分布
and how they affect the distribution of and engagement
新闻和信息。
with news and information.
看来这个话题特别重要
It would seem that this topic is especially relevant
现在，鉴于最近的美国总统大选，政治内容已经
now, given the recent US presidential election, where political content has
一直主导着互联网和电视广播以及争议
been dominating the internet and television broadcasts and controversy
在社交媒体上大放异彩，赢得了关注
has played out on social media, garnering attention
来自世界各地的。
from around the world.
毫无疑问，技术已彻底革命
Undoubtedly, technology has completely revolutionized
信息和新闻的传播和消费方式。
the way information and news is both disseminated and consumed.
不要在纸上男孩大喊大叫，而是在街角把您的新闻放在这里，
Instead of a paper boy shouting, get your news here on the street corner,
几乎每个人都使用互联网熬夜
just about everyone uses the internet to stay up
迄今为止，不仅发生在本地，而且发生在世界各地。
to date with what's happening, not just locally, but around the world.
在过去的几年中，尤其是社交媒体平台，
And in the past few years, social media platforms, in particular,
在人们获取，分享，
have started to play a huge role in how people access, share,
并与信息互动。
and engage with information.
例如，研究表明，美国有44％的成年人
For instance, research shows that 44% of US adults
报告从Facebook获取新闻。
report getting the news from Facebook.
可以肯定地说，近年来发生了很多变化，
It's safe to say a lot has changed in recent years,
由于技术的发展。
owing to developments in technology.
当我们考虑关键问题时，这很重要，即能力
And this matters when we consider what's at stake, namely, the ability
公众参与的话语
for the public to engage in discourse that
支持运作良好的民主。
supports a well-functioning democracy.
首先，我将向您简要介绍我们的来源
So I'll first present you a brief overview of where we came from
以及我们现在的位置，由于技术的发展
and where we are now, owing to technological developments
然后考虑我们今天面临的挑战。
and then consider what challenges we're faced with today.
在上网之前，新闻和信息
Before the internet, news and information
几乎完全掌握在几个主要广播电台和印刷品的手中
was almost entirely in the hands of a few major broadcast stations and print
媒体渠道，也称为大众媒体领域。
media outlets, otherwise known as the mass media sphere.
由于一些组织负责传播
Since a few organizations were responsible for disseminating
所有的新闻，信息本质上是
all the news, information was essentially
通过狭窄的镜头或狭窄的光圈过滤
filtered through a narrow lens or narrow aperture
从组织到广大公众。
from organizations to a wide public audience.
负责研究和写作的记者
The journalists who are responsible for researching and writing
这些组织的内容都具有专业精神。
the content for these organizations all shared a professional ethos.
他们关心真理，社会团体的代表，
They were concerned with truth, representation of social groups,
创建一个批评论坛，阐明公共价值观，
creating a forum for criticism, clarifying public values,
并提供全面的覆盖范围。
and offering comprehensive coverage.
尤其是因为目标是生产
And notably, since the aim was to produce
吸引了广大观众的内容，
content that appealed to a wide audience,
如今，我们所看到的两极分化和极端主义评论较少。
there was less polarization and extremist commentary than we see today.
但是负责新闻报道的新闻记者
But the journalists responsible for news coverage
在很多方面都非常统一
were very uniform in a lot of ways.
有相对富裕，受过高等教育的人，大多数是白人，男性，
There were relatively affluent, highly educated, mostly white, male,
等等。
and so forth.
这影响了种族政治，经济政策，
And this had effects on the coverage of racial politics, economic policy,
以及对美国在世界上的作用的看法。
and views about the role of the US in the world.
而且，观众很少有机会
Moreover, there were seldom opportunities for the audience
做出回应，开发新的主题或主题，
to respond, to develop new themes or topics,
或针对大众传媒领域的批评。
or level criticism against the mass media sphere.
没有任何喜欢和评论的部分
There weren't any likes and comment sections
用于报纸或电视广播。
for the newspaper or television broadcasts.
如果您不喜欢它，那么，祝您好运。
If you didn't like it, well, tough luck.
近年来，这一切开始改变，
This all started to change in recent years,
因为新闻报道不仅转移到网上，而且转移到社交媒体平台上。
as news coverage not only moved online, but onto social media platforms.
我们现在生活在一个数字网络化的公共领域。
We now live in a digitally networked public sphere.
因此，与其进行狭窄的交流，
So instead of having a narrow aperture of communications,
或只有少数几个组织向公众传播信息，
or just a few organizations to disseminate information to the public,
我们现在有了一个大口径的数字领域，那里有很多人
we now have a digital sphere with a wide aperture, where lots of people
可以分享新闻和信息。
can share news and information.
更具体地说，内容的来源
More specifically, the sources of content
不仅是他们所雇用的组织和专业新闻工作者，
are not just organizations and the professional journalists they employed,
但公众，尤其是社交媒体用户。
but the public and particularly, social media users.
任何人都可以在Facebook上发推文或发布信息，任何人都可以
Anyone can tweet or post on Facebook, and anyone
可以阅读这些推文和帖子。
can read those tweets and posts.
不仅带来更大的多样性
It's not only resulted in greater diversity
内容，但也可以更好地访问信息。
of content, but greater access to information as well.
如果您想关注新闻，有很多选择
If you want to follow the news, there are a ton of options
以及在线免费场所，只需单击几下鼠标即可访问。
and free places online you can access with just a few mouse clicks.
增加多样性和获取机会的这些前景
These prospects of increased diversity and access
是什么导致许多人相信数字领域
are what led many people to believe that the digital sphere held
改善公众话语的巨大希望
great promise for improving the public discourse that
支持运作良好的民主。
supports a well-functioning democracy.
在某些方面，这是事实。
And in some ways, this has been true.
例如，感谢Twitter和Facebook，
For example, thanks to Twitter and Facebook,
我们看到了社会正义运动的动员，
we saw the mobilization of social justice movements,
像我，《太黑了》和《黑色生活》
like Me, Too and Black Lives Matter.
并且观点的多样性增加
And the increased diversity of perspectives
为个人研究人员和科学家提供了可能
made it possible for individual researchers and scientists
权衡CDC关于冠状病毒的主张。
to weigh in on the CDC'S claims about coronavirus.
因此，尽管CDC最初并未说冠状病毒是特征
So while the CDC did not initially say coronavirus was characterized
通过空中传播，导致社区扩散，
by airborne transmission, leading to community spread,
他们最终在科学家之后改变了自己的立场
they ended up revising their stance after scientists
拿到Twitter上的证据证明确实如此。
took to Twitter with evidence proving that this was the case.
尽管数字领域带来了一些进步，
While the digital sphere has brought about some improvements,
它还加剧了一些问题并带来了新的挑战。
it's also exacerbated some problems and created new challenges.
例如，由于任何人都可以创建内容，因此进行事实检查和监视
For example, since anyone can create content, fact checking and monitoring
已经变得更加困难。人们是
have become much more difficult. People are
在弄清楚是否有东西时要自己照顾自己
left to fend for themselves when it comes to figuring out whether something
他们在网上阅读是值得信赖的。
they read online is trustworthy.
我们还看到，尊重方面的个性化程度有所提高
We've also seen increased personalization with respect
新闻和信息，其中特定内容可以
to news and information, where specific content could
通过精选新闻将特定用户定位为特定用户
be targeted to specific users by the means of curated news
大量涌现社交媒体和有线电视新闻台
feeds on social media and cable news stations cropping up
他们所报道的新闻具有特殊的角度。
that take a particular angle on the news that they cover.
这很重要。
This is significant.
因为我们最终会产生某种自相矛盾的效果。
Because we end up with a somewhat paradoxical effect.
尽管可用内容的多样性更大，
Despite a greater diversity in the content that's available,
新闻和信息人员的多样性较少
there's less diversity in the news and information people
最终最终消耗掉了，信息的个性化
actually end up consuming, with the personalization of information having
倾向于强化一个人的观点，
a tendency to reinforce a person's viewpoints,
而不是挑战或扩大它们。
rather than challenge or broaden them.
此外，在缺乏集中新闻来源的情况下，
Additionally, in the absence of centralized sources of news,
我们还看到了创建和共享内容所表达的不同目标。
we've also seen different aims expressed by those creating and sharing content.
一些人绕开了对真理的关注，以争取更多的观点。
Some have bypassed a concern for truth in an effort to garner more views
并且喜欢带有极端主义内容或虚假新闻的人。
and likes with extremist content or fake news.
假新闻在当时成为一个巨大的问题
And fake news became a huge issue around the time
令人担忧的是2016年总统大选
of the 2016 presidential election, as there were concerns
错误信息在社交媒体上的大量传播
that the massive spread of misinformation on social media
可能影响或影响个人的政治观点。
could influence or sway individuals political views.
尽管错误信息的传播一直是一个问题，
While the spread of misinformation has always been an issue,
数字公共领域确实加剧了这种情况，
it's truly been exacerbated by the digital public sphere,
社交媒体平台实质上是将汽油浇在火上。
with social media platforms essentially pouring gasoline on the fire.
假新闻的传播在社交媒体上激增
The dissemination of fake news explodes on social media
因为数字环境的结构，从喜欢到转发，
because the structure of digital environments, from likes to retweets,
允许有关假新闻的单个帖子广为传播，
allows a single post on fake news to go viral,
到达全世界数以百万计的屏幕。
reaching the screens of millions around the world.
而且，对于假新闻如何发挥作用也存在严重的担忧
And there are serious worries about how fake news has played a role
加剧政治上的两极分化。
in amplifying political polarization.
因此，尽管技术带来了独特的优势，
So while technology has made possible unique advantages,
它也带来了独特的挑战。
it's also brought on unique challenges.
我们现在面临的一个主要问题
One major question that we're faced with now
正在研究如何在社交媒体平台上对内容进行监管，
is figuring out how content should be regulated on social media platforms,
如果有的话。
if at all.
考虑到问题的严重性，有些人可能会持怀疑态度，
Given the scale of the problem, some might be skeptical,
认为任何形式的内容监管都是不可能的。
believing that any form of content regulation would be impossible.
在线发布的人太多，无法对所有事实进行事实检查。
There's just too many people posting online to fact check them all.
假新闻传播如此之快，很难在它已经停止之前停止
And fake news spreads so quickly, it's hard to stop before it's already
吸引了很多观众
reached a huge audience.
还有担心会试图调节
There's also worries that attempts to regulate
内容最终可能会成为一种违背审查制度的形式
content could end up becoming a form of censorship that violates
言论自由权。
the right to freedom of speech.
但是有些人对这种可能性更加乐观
But some people are more optimistic about the possibilities
以促进和保存的方式设计社交媒体平台的过程
of designing social media platforms in a way that promotes and preserves
民主。
democracy.
特别是，负责任的设计
In particular, there's a possibility that with responsibly designed
算法和用户界面选择，我们
algorithms and user interface choices, we
也许能够减缓虚假新闻的传播
might be able to slow the spread of fake news
并从总体上改善信息的传播和参与方式
and more generally improve the ways information is disseminated and engaged
与社交媒体上。
with on social media.
例如，有些人认为Facebook，Twitter等公司
For example, some people believe that companies like Facebook, Twitter
YouTube负责规范内容
and YouTube have a responsibility to regulate content
因为他们对我们有巨大的影响。
because of the enormous influence they have over us.
特别是，人们认为社交媒体平台有责任
In particular, it's thought that social media platforms have a responsibility
警戒虚假新闻并降低数据驱动算法的功能
to police fake news and reduce the power of data driven algorithms that
个性化用户体验，即使这样做
personalize the user experience, even if doing these things
将以用户参与为代价，
would come at the cost of user engagement,
从而减少了在平台上花费的时间，并减少了广告收入。
resulting in less time spent on the platform and less advertising revenue.
显然，就此而言，前进的道路
It's clear that the path going forward in terms
社交媒体平台上的内容监管将非常棘手。
of content regulation on social media platforms is going to be tricky.
我们是否提倡民主理想或破坏民主理想
Whether or not we promote democratic ideals or undermine
他们将取决于我们做出的特定设计选择。
them will come down to the particular design choices we make.
为了使用技术创造解决方案
In order to use technology to create solutions
面对我们今天面临的问题，我们将
to the problems we're facing today, we'll
需要就设计选择做出明智的决定。
need to make informed decisions about design choices.
这需要对道德和哲学进行批判性思考
And this requires some critical thinking about ethics and philosophy
找出执行此操作的最佳方法。
to figure out the best way to do this.
但是我们希望像您一样的学生参加CS50，
But we're hoping that students like you, taking CS50,
可以利用您的创造力，技术知识和道德推理
can harness your creativity, technical knowledge, and ethical reasoning
以负责任的方式设计技术。
to design technology in a responsible way.
所以我现在要把事情交给梅卡，
So I'm now going to pass things over to Meica,
谁会告诉你一些哲学概念
who will tell you about some philosophical concepts that'll
帮助您主动思考特定的设计
help you think proactively about particular design
可以实现结构的选择和算法工具
choices and algorithmic tools that can be implemented to structure
社交媒体平台，以促进民主公众话语的方式。
social media platforms in a way that promotes democratic public discourse.
MEICA MAGNANI：在民主与数字公共领域，
MEICA MAGNANI: In Democracy and The Digital Public Sphere,
一篇可以很好地诊断我们情况的文章，
an article which offers a fantastic diagnosis of our situation,
苏珊和我从中大量汲取金钱
and from which Susan and I are drawing heavily
在本次演讲中，作者约书亚·科恩（Joshua Cohen）和冯宗Arch（Archon Fung）
upon for this lecture, the authors Joshua Cohen and Archon Fung,
告诉我们，数字玫瑰绽放了。
tell us that the bloom is off the digital rose.
正如苏珊（Susan）所描述的，我们寄予厚望
As Susan was describing, we had such high hopes
为社交媒体和互联网的民主化潜力。
for the democratizing potential of social media and the internet.
但是现在我们面临假新闻泛滥的环境，
But now we face an environment in which fake news runs rampant,
市民似乎两极分化，
citizens appear to be dramatically polarized,
信息在它自己的孤立气泡中回旋，
information swirls in its own isolated bubbles,
仇恨言论达到令人震惊的硫酸水平。
and hate speech reaches appalling levels of vitriol.
所有这些都会威胁到人们的猜测，
All of which stand to threaten, or so people speculate,
有效民主所需的条件。
the conditions required for an effective democracy.
所以出现以下问题，以什么方式
So the following questions arise, in what ways
民主的条件受到威胁吗？
are the conditions of democracy threatened?
对此可以或应该做些什么？
What can or should be done about it?
我们的技术结构负责吗？
Is the structure of our technology responsible?
还是我们作为人类创造了这些问题？
Or is it just us, as human beings, creating these problems?
在本模块中，我们将重点关注
In this module, we're focusing specifically
关于内容监管的问题。
on the issue of content regulation.
社交媒体公司，例如Twitter，Facebook和YouTube
Social media companies like Twitter, Facebook, and YouTube
现在都在尝试通过平台解决这些问题
are now all in the game of trying to address these problems through platform
设计和功能。
design and features.
从一个角度来看，他们正在为维护民主服务
From one angle then, they are acting in the service of protecting democracy
通过试图控制错误信息的传播，
by trying to get control over the spread of misinformation,
仇恨言论的放大和两极分化的加深。
the amplification of hate speech, and the deepening of polarization.
但是，从另一个角度来看，他们正在介入
However, from another angle, they're stepping in
塑造信息的分布。
to shape the distribution of information.
根据特定的设计选择，
And depending on the particular design choices,
可能被设置为调节或沉默
might be set to be regulating or silencing
演讲，这当然与民主承诺背道而驰
speech, which of course, is at odds with democratic commitments
言论自由和话语权。
to free speech and discourse.
然后，本模块的重点是为您提供一些工具
The point of this module, then, is to give you some tools
思考这些问题，了解问题的工具，
to think through these issues, tools for understanding the problem,
诊断问题的根源，并集思广益。
diagnosing the sources of the problem, and brainstorming solutions.
在剩下的10或15分钟内，我要去
In the remaining 10 or 15 minutes, I'm going
提供主要工具的概述
to provide an overview of the main tools which
您将在阅读材料中找到详细信息。
you will find detailed in the readings.
它们也是您将需要在本周的实验室中进行分析的工具。
They are also the tools you will be asked to analyze in this week's lab.
所以首先，我们需要清楚地考虑一下
So first then, we need to think clearly about what
健康的民主是必需的。
is required for a healthy democracy.
如果我们要宣称技术如何威胁民主，
If we're going to be making claims about how tech threatens democracy,
我们更好地了解A，什么是民主，B，什么样的条件
we better understand A, what a democracy is, and B, what sort of conditions
支持民主，使这些条件可能受到威胁。
support democracy, such that those conditions could come under threat.
政治学教授冯宗宪在他们的文章中
In their article, Archon Fung, who is a professor in political science
在哈佛大学和政治哲学家约书亚·科恩（Joshua Cohen）一起工作
here at Harvard, and Joshua Cohen, who is a political philosopher now working
与苹果大学的教职员工一起，为我们提供这些工具。
with the faculty at Apple University, provide us with these tools.
因此，在民主理念背后是理想的选择
So behind the idea of democracy is an ideal
政治社会应该是什么。
of what political society should be.
冯和科恩将此理想简化为三个要素。
Fung and Cohen reduce this ideal to three elements.
首先，民主社会的思想
First, the idea of a democratic society, a society
政治文化将个人视为自由和平等。
in which the political culture views individuals as free and equal.
即使这些人可能
Even though it is likely that these people have
不同的利益，身份和信仰体系，作为公民，
different interests, identities, and systems of belief, as citizens,
他们致力于通过反思和话语到达原则
they are committed to arriving m through reflection and discourse, principles
这将使他们能够在尊重自由的同时共同努力
that will enable them to work together while respecting their freedom
和平等。
and equality.
其次是民主政治体制的思想，
Second is the idea of a democratic political regime, which
其特点是定期选举，参与权，
is characterized by regular elections, rights of participation,
以及关联权和表达权
along with associative and expressive rights
使参与既有见地又有效。
that make participation both informed and effective.
第三，最后是协商民主的思想，
Third and lastly is the idea of a deliberative democracy,
根据哪个政治讨论
according to which political discussion should
诉诸适合合作的理由
appeal to reasons that are suitable for cooperation
自由平等的人之间。
amongst free and equal persons.
因此，在为一项政策辩护时，您不能诉诸于自己的宗教信仰，
So in justifying a policy, you cannot appeal to, say, your own religion,
鉴于其他人不一定持有相同的信念。
given that others do not necessarily hold those same beliefs.
您可以诉诸宗教自由的概念，但不能
You can appeal to the notion of, say, religious freedom, but not
宗教本身所包含的特定信仰。
the particular beliefs contained within the religion itself.
因此，民主基本上是一种理想
So democracy, then, is basically an ideal
我们通过集体决策来控制自己，
that we govern ourselves by collective decision making, decision making that
尊重我们的自由与平等。
respects our freedom and equality.
这项决策不仅包括正式的投票程序，
This decision making consists not only of the formal procedures of voting,
选举和立法，也由非正式的公共领域提供信息，
elections, and legislation, it is also informed by the informal public sphere,
也就是说，公民发现问题和关切，
that is, citizens identifying problems and concerns,
讨论和辩论问题，表达意见，挑战
discussing and debating problems, expressing opinions, challenging
观点，并围绕原因进行组织。
viewpoints, and organizing around causes.
这是民主决策过程中绝对关键的部分。
This is an absolutely critical part of the democratic decision-making process.
在这里，我们作为公众形成，测试，分散，交流，
It is where we, as the public, form, test, disperse, exchange,
挑战，并修改我们的观点。
challenge, and revise our views.
信息流以及用户参与度
The flow of information, along with user engagement
在Facebook，YouTube和Twitter上都是
on Facebook, YouTube, and Twitter, are all part
这个非正式的公共领域。
of this informal public sphere.
为了个人可以参与
In order that individuals can participate
在这个公共演讲舞台上作为自由和平等的公民，
as free and equal citizens in this arena of public discourse,
Cohen和Fung提出了一系列权利和机会
Cohen and Fung lay out a set of rights and opportunities
一个运作良好的民主国家将需要的。
that a well-functioning democracy will require.
这些是提供的分析工具。
And these are the tools of analysis on offer.
首先，权利。
So first, rights.
“作为民主国家的公民，我们享有权利
"As citizens of a democracy, we have rights
基本自由，表达自由和结社自由。
to basic liberties, liberties of expression and association.
表达自由权很重要
The right to expressive liberty is important
不仅为了个人的自由，
not only for the freedom of the individual,
这样他或她就不会受到审查，而且也会受到民主本身的审查。
so that he or she will not be censored, but also for democracy itself.
它使公民能够将他们的想法相互交流
It enables citizens to bring their ideas into conversation with one another
并批评和追究行使权力的人。”
and to criticize and hold accountable those who exercise power."
第二是表达的机会。
Second is the opportunity for expression.
“我们不仅应该不受审查，而且
"Not only should we be free of censorship, but
我们应该有公平的机会参加公开讨论。
we should have fair opportunity to participate in public discussion.
并非应该因为某人是这样，
It shouldn't be the case that because someone is, say,
富裕或更强大，他们就有更多参与的机会。”
wealthier or more powerful, that they have more opportunity to participate."
第三是访问。
Third is access.
“每个人都应享有平等的机会
"Each person should have good and equal access
获得有关公共事务的质量可靠的信息。
to quality and reliable information on public matters.
也就是说，如果我们付出努力，我们应该
That is, if we make the effort, we should
能够获取此信息。
be able to acquire this information.
有效参与决策需要知情。”
Effective participation in decision making requires being informed."
第四是多样性。
Fourth is diversity.
“每个人都应该有平等机会听取各种各样的意见。
"Each person should have good and equal chances to hear a wide range of views.
我们需要获得竞争观点才能拥有
We need access to competing views in order to have
更加明智和理性的立场”
a more informed and reasoned position"
最后，第五，沟通能力。
And lastly, number five, communicative power.
“公民应有平等机会探索兴趣和思想
"Citizens should have good and equal chances to explore interests and ideas
与他人合作。
in association with others.
通过这些协会，发展出新的关注点，
And through these associations, to develop new concerns that
可能会挑战主流观点。”
might challenge the mainstream view."
这些权利和机会共同提供了关键条件
These rights and opportunities together provide critical conditions
使人们能够参与公共讨论。
for enabling participation in public discussion.
他们可能需要跟踪很多东西，
They might seem like a lot to keep track of initially,
但是如果我们要思考一下社交媒体如何威胁民主，
but if we're going to think through how social media threatens democracy,
更具体地说，平台设计如何促进或阻碍民主，
and more concretely, how platform design might promote or hinder democracy,
这些都是有价值的工具。
these are valuable tools.
我们可以使用访问条件，想法
We can use, say, the access condition, the idea
我们所有人都应该能够获得可靠的信息，
that we should all have access to reliable information,
作为分析的镜头。
as a lens of analysis.
我们的平台是否阻止某些群体或用户
Does our platform prevent certain groups or users
从访问可靠的信息？
from accessing reliable information?
或者我们可以使用多样性条件
Or we can use the diversity condition, the idea
我们所有人都应该可以访问多种矛盾的观点
that we should all have access to a plurality of conflicting views
作为分析的镜头。
as a lens of analysis.
例如，我们可能会问自己，我们的平台是否
So for example, we might ask ourselves, does our platform
创建一个过滤泡，使个人不再面对
create a filter bubble in which individuals are no longer confronted
有反对意见？
with opposing views?
除了了解什么条件支持
In addition to understanding what conditions support
一个民主社会，我们还需要了解所谓的问题
a democratic society, we also need to understand the purported problems
在我们提出有效的干预措施之前。
before we can propose effective interventions.
考虑假新闻。
Consider fake news.
当涉及到假新闻时，为什么人们这么容易被骗呢？
Why are people so gullible when it comes to fake news?
为什么他们经常在没有适当的严格评估的情况下重新发布？
Why do they often repost without proper critical assessment?
里贾纳·里尼（Regina Rini）在阅读中建议
Regina Rini, in the reading, proposes that in order
了解假新闻现象，
to understand the phenomenon of fake news,
我们应该把它当作证词的一种形式。
we should think about it as a form of testimony.
当其他人与您共享信息时，
When another person shares information with you,
您通常会认为它是真实的。
you typically take it to be true.
这是因为规范我们作证行为的准则。
This is because of the norms governing our practice of testimony.
当您断言某些东西，并将其传递给其他人时，
When you assert something, passing it on to others,
您通常会对它的真实性负责。
you typically take responsibility for its truth.
假设您已获得证据
It is assumed that you have either acquired evidence
为您自己，或者您已从某个来源收到此信息
for yourself or you've received this information from a source
您认为可靠。
that you deem reliable.
我们对世界的大部分了解都来自这种实践。
Most of our knowledge about the world comes through this practice.
我们不可能获得所有我们持有的信念的证据。
We could not possibly acquire evidence for all the beliefs we hold.
因此，我们常常不得不依靠我们认为并希望可信的资源。
So we often have to rely on sources we deem and hope to be credible.
但里尼指出，社交媒体尚未制定出推荐规范。
But social media, Rini points out, has unsettled testimonial norms.
当某人发布一条新闻时，我们似乎持有两种相互矛盾的观点。
When someone posts a piece of news, we seem to hold two conflicting views.
一方面，我们认为这是积极的认可。
On the one hand, we see it as an active endorsement.
发布者已承担了一定程度的责任
The person posting has taken some degree of responsibility
为了他们的帖子的准确性，以相同的方式之一
for the accuracy of their post, the same way one
在进行对话之前传递信息。
would before passing on information in a conversation.
但另一方面，这只是一部分。
On the other hand, though, it's just a share.
当唐纳德·特朗普大声疾呼时，我们会看到这种态度
We see this attitude coming through when Donald Trump, called out
在他的一条可疑推文中，用eh反驳，这只是一条推文。
on one of his questionable tweets, retorts with, eh, it's just a tweet.
为了打击假新闻，Rini认为我们
To fight fake news, then, Rini argues that we
需要稳定社交媒体的证词规范，以便如她所说，
need to stabilize social media's norms of testimony so that, as she says,
保持我们对鸡尾酒诚实的相同准则
the same norms that keep us honest over cocktails
将使我们对自己的职位保持诚实。
will keep us honest in our posts.
我们需要对人们负责，
We need people to be held accountable for,
或对信息负有责任感
or to have a sense of responsibility, for the information
他们与他人分享。
that they share with others.
她的具体建议，给用户一个信誉分数。
Her concrete proposal, give users a credibility score.
因此，实际上，这将是对Facebook系统的修正，
So in practice, this would be an amendment to Facebook's system,
使用独立的事实检查组织，
using independent fact checking organizations,
Facebook会标记有问题的新闻，并在用户重新发布之前警告用户。
Facebook flags problematic news and warns users before they repost it.
当用户尝试发布已确定的内容时
When a user tries to post something that has been identified
如果是错误或误导性内容，则会出现一个弹出窗口，说明问题所在
as false or misleading, a pop up appears that explains the problem
并标识原始来源。
and identifies the original source.
然后，它要求用户确认他们会
It then asks the user to confirm that they would
喜欢继续他们的转发。
like to continue with their repost.
对于Rini，用户的信誉分数将
A user's credibility score, for Rini, would
取决于他们选择忽略这些警告的频率
depend on how often they choose to ignore these warnings
并传递误导性信息。
and pass on misleading information.
引用，“用户名旁边的绿点可以
Quote, "a green dot by the user's name could
表示用户未选择分享很多有争议的新闻。
indicate that the user hasn't chosen to share much disputed news.
黄点可能表示他们有时会这样做。
A yellow dot could indicate that they do it sometimes.
红色可能表明他们经常这样做。”
And a red could indicate that they do it often."
取消报价。
Unquote.
那么，想法就是信誉分数
The idea, then, is that a credibility score
会激励用户承担责任
would incentivize users to take responsibility
他们分享的东西，也会使别人对他们的信赖感
for what they share and would also give others a sense of their reliability
作为来源。
as sources.
因此，Rini经过仔细分析后提出了此解决方案
So Rini comes up with this solution through a careful analysis
为什么我们如此容易冒充假新闻。
of why we are so gullible to fake news.
我留给你考虑这个建议
I will leave it up to you to consider this proposal
根据所需的各种权利和机会
in light of the various rights and opportunities required
民主的公共领域。
for a democratic public sphere.
里尼的提议是否侵犯或威胁了言论自由？
Does Rini's proposal violate or threaten freedom of expression?
它是否促进或阻碍了我们对可靠信息的访问，我们的访问
Does it promote or hinder our access to reliable information, our access
观点的多样性，还是促进或阻碍了
to diversity of views, or does it promote or hinder
我们的沟通能力？
our communicative power?
我们希望这些问题是
It is these sorts of questions that we hope
在思考时会开始问自己
that you will start to ask yourself when thinking
通过以下问题。
through the following sorts of issues.
假新闻，仇恨言论，两极分化等问题会发生什么
What problems do fake news, hate speech, polarization, et cetera
对民主构成？
pose to democracy?
Twitter，YouTube，
How successful are various attempts by companies like Twitter, YouTube,
和Facebook解决这些问题？
and Facebook to address these problems?
以及社交媒体平台的特定设计功能如何
And how might particular design features of social media platforms
促进或阻碍这些特殊的权利和机会？
promote or hinder these particular rights and opportunities?
无论是作为未来的计算机科学家，技术行业的领导者，
Whether as a future computer scientist, a tech industry leader,
或只是作为这些技术的用户，我们希望问这些问题
or just as a user of these technologies, we hope asking these sorts of questions
将帮助您更审慎地解决这些棘手的问题。
will help you navigate these tricky issues with a more critical eye.
苏珊·肯尼迪：我们真的很期待各种各样的设计选择
SUSAN KENNEDY: We're really looking forward to the sorts of design choices
你将来会做的。
that you'll be making in the future.
MEICA MAGNANI：太好了。
MEICA MAGNANI: Great.
非常感谢您今天有我们来这里。
Thanks so much for having us here today.
祝大家好运。
And best of luck to everybody.
DAVID MALAN：好的，非常感谢Susan和Meica加入我们的行列。
DAVID MALAN: Well, thank you so much to Susan and Meica for joining us.
确实，在接下来的一周的实验中，我们将有机会
Indeed, in this coming week's lab, we'll have an opportunity
在一些非常大的背景下考虑其中的一些问题
to consider some of these issues in the context of some very
特定的现实世界场景。
specific real world scenarios.
因此，我们现在认为我们将期待您可以做的事情
So we now thought we would take a look forward at what you can do
以及CS50之后的处理方式
and how you can do it after CS50 when it comes
超出了计算思维本身的实际范围。
to the more practical side of things beyond computational thinking alone.
因此，当然，对于许多人来说，
So programming, of course, for many of you,
这将是设计使然的唯一计算机科学或编程课程
this will be by design the only computer science or programming course
你拿的。
that you take.
那当然可以。
And that's certainly OK.
确实，我们希望您现在能够返回
Indeed, we hope that you'll be able now to return
您对艺术和人文科学，社会科学感兴趣的领域，
to your own domains of interest in the arts and humanities, social sciences,
或科学，实际上能够拥有一套具体的实践技能
or sciences and actually be able to have a concrete set of practical skills
是使用Python还是C或任何其他技术语言编写的
be it in Python or C or any of the other technical languages
我们研究并可以实际解决您自己喜欢的领域中的问题。
we looked at and can actually solve problems in your own preferred domain.
如果您有兴趣了解有关计算机科学的更多信息
And if you're interested in learning more about computer science
本身，并在那个世界上前进，我们希望
itself and moving on in that world, we hope
您将拥有坚实的基础
that you'll walk away with a solid foundation
以便对该特定领域进行进一步的理论和系统探索。
for further theoretical and systematic explorations of this particular field.
但实际上，我们希望现在
But very practically speaking, we hope now
这样，您不仅可以编程，而且可以更好地提出问题，
that you can not only program, but also ask questions better,
无论是在技术世界还是在现实世界中。
whether that's in the technical world or even in just the real world.
奇怪的是，如果您曾经在CS50的论坛上提问，
Odds are, if you've ever asked a question on CS50's discussion forums,
老师或我可能很好地回答了问题
the teaching fellows or I might have very well responded with questions
请您澄清一下。
asking you to clarify.
或者更好的是，您会在预期中为我们提供，
Or better yet, you would have provided us, in anticipation,
回答我们可能遇到的所有问题。
with answers to all of the questions that we might have.
如果您在Ed上注意到了，我们特意
And if you've noticed on Ed, we deliberately
有这样的模板，您可以通过
have this sort of template via which you're
哄着回答，您看到的是什么症状？
coaxed to answer, well, what are the symptoms that you are seeing?
您遇到的错误消息是什么？
What's the error message that you're struggling with?
您尝试采取什么步骤解决此问题？
What steps have you tried to resolve the problem?
因为如果我们在现实世界中进行想象，即使只是伸出手
Because if we imagine in the real world, even just reaching out
到一些随机公司的客户服务热线，
to some random company's customer service line,
这些恰恰是别人提出的那种问题
those are exactly the kinds of questions that someone else
将不得不请你更好地了解
is going to have to ask you to better understand
从您自己的角度来看问题。
a problem from your own perspective.
因此，当您从CS50本身诞生时，我们鼓励您考虑一下，
And so we would encourage you to think about, as you emerge from CS50 itself,
只是如何向人们提出更好的问题。
just how to ask better questions of people.
如果您有比他们更多的信息，
If you've got more information than they,
您如何简洁却正确地将信息传达给他们
how can you succinctly but correctly convey that information to them
以便他们可以更有效地帮助您。
so that they can help you more efficiently.
而且，找到答案。
But also, finding answers.
就像，我们绝对理解CS50的许多周，CS50的所有周，
Like, we absolutely understand that many of CS50's weeks, all of CS50's weeks,
也许，已经很无奈了。
maybe, have been quite the frustration.
因为您经常会觉得，好吧，我们在讲座中没有涉及到这一点。
Because you quite often feel like, well, we didn't cover that in lecture.
或者我没有在本节中看到这一点。
Or I didn't see that in section.
我看到头有些点头。
And I see some noddings of the head.
因此，似乎是这种情况。
So this seems to be the case.
就像我很想保证的那样，
And much as I would love to reassure otherwise, like,
这是非常有意图的。
that was very much the intent.
因为像这样的任何课程的最后一个训练轮
Because the last of the training wheels of any course like this
现在真的确实正式起飞了。
now really do officially come off.
在接下来的几周中，我们仍然
And in the coming weeks, while we'll still
与您一起为最终项目助一臂之力
be with you to lend a hand with final projects
并按照这些思路回答问题，
and answer questions along those lines, there's
当然，最终项目的规范没有告诉您确切的操作，
of course no specification for the final project telling you exactly what to do,
或使用哪种语言或使用哪种库。
or in what language to do it, or what libraries to use.
无疑，在接下来的几周中，您将
Undoubtedly, in the coming weeks, you will
遇到以前从未见过的错误消息。
run into error messages you haven't even seen before.
坦白说，也许我，也许布莱恩，也许是助教，
And frankly, maybe I, maybe Brian, maybe the teaching assistants,
而且课程助理甚至从未见过这些错误。
and the course assistants haven't even seen those errors before.
但是，当然，目标是以某种方式使您克服这些障碍
But the goal, of course, is to get you over those hurdles in a way
您可以找出如何自行执行这些操作的方法。
that you can figure out how to do those things on your own.
因此，仅使用互联网时，无论是Google还是Stack
And so when it comes to just using the internet, be it Google, or Stack
溢出或与其他人互动，
Overflow, or interacting with other humans,
只是在编程世界中找到答案
just finding answers when it comes to the world of programming
或实际上只是更广泛地解决问题的世界，
or really just the world of problem solving more generally,
我们希望这实际上是一种持久的技能。
we hope that is actually a lasting skill.
我们希望您能够做到无可奈何地做到这一点，
And we hope that you've been able to do that with admittedly frustration,
但是这几个月来，您的课程都拥有安全网。
but with the safety net of the course underneath you all these months.
但是，从现在开始，我们希望您再舒适一点，再舒服一点
But here on out, we hope you'll be more comfortable, again, being uncomfortable
当您发现新事物时。
as you figure out new things.
其中一部分只是阅读文档。
And part of that is just reading documentation.
在这里，这也是一种挫败感，它很可能永远不会消失。
And here, too, this is a frustration that may very well never go away.
像是某些语言或库的一些文档，
Like, some documentation out there for certain languages or libraries, just
不好
isn't good.
它是由那些不认为的人写的
It was written by people that just don't think
像您或我一样，不要以您所希望的同理心思考。
like you or I do, don't think with the same form of empathy as you might hope.
因此，它是在非常低的技术细节水平下编写的，
And therefore, it's written at a very low level of technical detail,
而且他们不仅仅告诉您该函数的作用。
and they don't just tell you what does the function do.
或者相反，它写得太高了，我的上帝，
Or conversely, it's written at such a high level that, my God,
您必须开始查看库的源代码
you have to start looking at the source code of the library
甚至弄清楚如何使用它。
to even figure out how to use it.
您将看到两个极端。
And you will see both extremes.
但是，您可以轻松阅读Python文档等内容，
But getting comfortable with reading things like Python's documentation,
就像某些API文档将帮助您一样，我们希望，
like some API's documentation is just going to empower you, we hope,
更要做些更酷的事情
all the more to just do much cooler things
并最终自行解决更强大的问题。
and solve more powerful problems on your own, ultimately.
最后，这也许是最大的一个，教你
And then lastly, and this is perhaps the biggest one, teaching you
如何教自己新的语言。
how to teach yourself new languages.
我们没有在Python上花费太多时间是有原因的。
There is a reason we didn't spend that much time on Python.
而且我们在JavaScript上花费的时间更少。
And we spent even less time on JavaScript.
在SQL上的时间差不多。
And about an equal amount of time on SQL.
我们花了几周时间在C上，不是因为C
We spent a number of weeks on C, not because C
比任何一种语言都重要，
is more important than any of those languages,
但是因为一路走来，你们中的很多人
but because along the way, many of you, most of you
只是在学习编程本身。
were just learning programming itself.
即使随着课程的进行语言发生了变化和发展，
And even as the language has changed and evolved as the course went on,
想法并没有消失。
the ideas didn't go away.
仍然有函数，条件，循环，甚至
There were still functions, and conditions, and loops, and even
事件的条款。
events by terms.
再说一遍，所以我们希望您不要参加这样的课程
And, again, so we hope that you walk away from a class like this
没想到，哦，我学会了用C语言编程。
not thinking that, oh, I learned how to program in C.
或者，哦，我学会了如何用Python编程。
Or oh, I learned how to program in Python.
因为我们还没有人是这些方面的专家。
Because none of us have been experts at those things yet.
但是您现在肯定会变得更加熟练，只是成为一名程序员
But you certainly are now more expert at just being a programmer
找出需要填补哪些知识的漏洞，什么
and figuring out what holes you need to fill in in your knowledge, what
您需要填补空白才能弄清楚，
gaps you need to fill in order to figure out,
哦，这种语言中相同方法的语法是什么
oh, what is the syntax for this same approach in this language
正如我已经在另一个地方看到的那样。
as I've already seen in another.
这就是为什么我们比较了许多这样的语言的原因
And that's, indeed, why we compared so many of these languages side
并肩而立，只是强调想法没有什么不同，甚至
by side to just reinforce that the ideas are no different, even
尽管语法需要使用大量Google搜索，也需要大量询问。
though the syntax is going to require a bunch of Googling, a bunch of asking.
这也是我们希望您能够自己做的事情
And that, too, is something we hope you'll be able to do on your own
在这些语言之后，下一件事就是最好的事情。
as the next and best thing comes along well after these languages.
好吧，说到训练轮，你就是
Well, speaking of training wheels, you're
欢迎并鼓励您在最终项目中继续使用CS50 IDE。
welcome and encouraged to keep using CS50 IDE for your final project.
而且，您甚至可以将其用于其他课程或项目。
And heck, you can use it even after that for other courses or projects.
但归根结底，这也可能是一个训练轮
But at the end of the day, this, too, is probably a training wheel
你应该自己起飞。
that you should take off for yourself.
IDE旨在代表现实世界中的编程
The IDE is designed to be representative of a real world programming
环境。
environment.
但是我们绝对为您做了很多事情。
But we definitely did a lot of things for you.
我们安装了您可能需要的所有库
We installed all the libraries you might need over
本学期的课程。
the course of the semester for you.
我们有这些漂亮的命令以数字50结尾。
We've got these nice commands that end in the number 50.
当您从事第一份工作时，那些往往不存在于现实世界中，
Those don't tend to exist in the real world when you're at your first job,
或者你要回到自己的部门
or you're going back to your own department
解决代码中的一些问题
and solving some problem in code, there's
不会成为长期的help50。
not going to be a help50 longer term.
因此，我们认为我们也将花费几分钟
And so what we thought we would do, too, is spend just a few minutes
让您大致了解一些行业标准
giving you a sense of what are some of the more industry standard
您应该考虑使用，玩耍的工具
tools that you should consider using, playing with, perhaps
过度休息或在接下来的几个月里，以便您确切地知道该怎么做
over break or in the months to come, so that you know exactly how to do
与本学期一样，但在您自己的Mac上
the same kinds of things you did this term, but on your own Mac
或PC或其他设备。
or PC or some other device.
因此，例如，如果您想安装一组命令行工具
So for instance, if you would like to install a set of command line tools
在Mac或PC上，事实证明其中有些已经存在。
on your Mac or PC, turns out some of them are already there.
确实，我曾经提到Mac OS
Indeed, I mentioned at one point that Mac OS
在其应用程序文件夹实用程序的终端下有一个终端窗口。
has under its applications folder utility's terminal a terminal window.
Windows也有类似的东西。
And Windows has an analog as well.
但是Mac或PC不一定附带其他命令，
But there's other commands that don't necessarily come with your Mac or PC,
例如，用于C或其他工具的编译器。
for instance, a compiler for C or some other tools.
因此，我们鼓励您在Mac或PC上访问此类网址，
And so we would encourage you to visit URLs like these on your Mac or PC,
分别，如果您只想安装更多的命令行工具
respectively, if you'd like to just install more of the command line tools
您在自己的环境中在CS50中看到和使用的内容。
that you saw and used in CS50 in your own environment.
我们建议您阅读另一种工具，在这种情况下，请继续阅读
Another tool we would recommend that you read up on, or in this case
观看，布莱恩（Brian）的视频是吉特（Git）。
watch, a video by Brian, is Git.
Git是版本控制的一个示例，它是基础构建
Git is an example of version control, a fundamental building
这些天来，任何好的软件实践都无法实现。
block of any good software practice these days.
我们在CS50中使用了Git，但是我们向您隐藏了此细节。
We kind of use Git in CS50, but we hide this detail from you.
每当您运行check50或Submit50时，我们都会在后台进行检查，
Any time you have run check50 or submit50, we underneath the hood,
一直在运行一个名为Git的开源命令，该命令会推送您的代码，
have been running an open source command called Git, which pushes your code,
在这种情况下，从CS50 IDE到GitHub.com，这仅仅是一个
in this case from CS50 IDE to GitHub.com, which is just one
几个热门网站中，您可以通过
of several popular websites via which you
可以托管代码，共享代码，在代码上进行协作，运行自动化测试，
can host code, share code, collaborate on code, run automated tests,
等等。
and the like.
但是Git本身可以用来终止约定
But Git itself can be used to put an end to the convention
即使是Microsoft Word或Google Docs之类的东西，您也可能拥有
that you probably have, even with things like Microsoft Word or Google Docs,
当您想保存某些内容或文件的另一个副本时，
where when you want to save something or another copy of a file,
也许您只是将文件名的末尾更改为2，
maybe you just changed the end of the file name to 2,
然后下一次到3或4。
and then the next time to 3, or to 4.
或者，也许您在星期日晚上破折号，在星期一早晨破折号。
Or maybe you do dash Sunday night, dash Monday morning.
我的意思是，有时我仍然为此感到内gui
I mean, I'm still guilty of this sometimes when I
想要对我的文件进行版本控制。
want to version my files.
有更好的方法可以做到这一点。
There are better ways to do that.
因此，如果您将来发现自己，
And so if you find yourself in the future,
做一些您认为必须有更好方法的事情，
doing something that you think there's got to be a better way,
Git是这些更好方法之一的示例。
Git is an example of one of those better ways.
如果您观看此特定视频，请阅读
And if you watch this particular video, read
从本质上讲，它不仅可以帮助您维护多个版本，
up a bit more, it will help you not only maintain multiple versions, in essence,
您自己的代码的备份，它最终还将使您有能力
backups of your own code, it will also empower you ultimately
与他人合作。
to collaborate with others.
至于文字编辑器，您可能会使用的工具
As for text editors, the tool that you might
用于实际编写代码，也许是最新，最出色和最先进的代码之一
use to actually write code, perhaps one of the latest and greatest and most
这些天流行的是称为VS Code的东西。
popular out there these days is something called VS Code.
这是一个开放源代码工具，您可以在自己的Mac和PC上下载。
This is an open source tool that you can download on your own Mac and PCs.
它也越来越多地在网络上可用。
Increasingly, it's available on the web as well.
但这无疑是当今最受欢迎的工具之一。
But this is one of the most popular tools, certainly, out there today.
但这只是一个文本编辑器。
But it's just a text editor.
这些工具中的每一个都有绝对的替代品
And there are absolutely alternatives to each and every one of these tools
当然也欢迎您来看看。
that you're certainly welcome to take a look at as well.
好吧，如果您对事物的网络方面感兴趣，
Well, if you're interested in the web side of things,
而您想要托管一个网站（例如静态网站），
and you want to host a website, like a static website, just
您自己的个人主页，GitHub页面就是一回事。
your own personal homepage, GitHub pages is a thing.
Netlify是一回事。
Netlify is a thing.
还有点点点滴滴，还有很多其他的虚拟主机，
And dot dot dot, there are so many other web hosts out there,
其中许多提供免费或学生级别
many of which offer free or student level
帐户，这样他们就不必花费任何费用。
accounts so that they don't necessarily need to even cost anything.
但是静态不同于动态。
But static is different from dynamic.
而且，如果您实际上想托管一个实际需要使用的Web应用程序，
And if you actually want to host a web application that actually takes
用户输入，将内容存储在数据库中，执行
user input, stores things in a database, does
比静态网站更有趣的事情，
more interesting things than a static website,
您可能想使用一种叫做Heroku的东西，
you might want to use something called Heroku, which is just
受欢迎的第三方服务，其中也包含您免费的入门级帐户
a popular third party service that also has a free entry level account that you
可以用来开始玩，很常用
can use to start playing with, quite commonly used
由学生进行最终项目。
by students for final projects.
然后还有其他提供商，更大的云提供商，
And then there's other providers out there, bigger cloud providers,
可以这么说，例如亚马逊，微软和谷歌，
so to speak, like Amazon, and Microsoft, and Google,
为此，学习曲线可能会更高一些。
for which the learning curve's perhaps a little higher.
但是它们通常在提供折扣方面也非常好
But they, too, are really good typically about providing discounts
或免费帐户供学生使用。
or free accounts for student uses as well.
如何与技术主题保持同步。
How to stay abreast of topics in technology.
当然，我们将重点放在此类基础知识上。
We focus, of course, in a class like this really on fundamentals.
但是您将无法以任何形式获取新闻
But you're not going to be able to pick up the news in any form down the road
却看不到与技术有关的东西。
and not see something that's technology related.
而且，如果您只是想让自己紧跟事物的脉搏
And if you'd just like to keep your fingers on the pulse of things
在更广泛的科技世界中，这里只有几个地方
in the tech world more generally, here's just a few places
您可能会喜欢与之并驾齐驱。
that you might enjoy staying abreast of.
因此，Reddit有几个不同的社区，即subreddit，特别是
So Reddit has a couple of different communities, or subreddit, specifically
关于编程的内容，都适合有经验的程序员
about programming, both for experienced programmers
和我们中那些仍在学习中的人。
and those of us who are still learning.
当然，堆栈溢出
Stack Overflow, of course, you've probably
在过去的学期中用于解决小问题。
used to solve small problems over the course of the past term.
服务器故障在本质上与此类似，
Server Fault is similar in spirit to that,
但它更侧重于管理以及Linux类型的内容。
but it's focused more on administration, Linux-type stuff as well.
Techcrunch是一个受欢迎的地方，不仅是面向消费者的新闻，
Techcrunch is a popular place, not just for consumer-focused news,
但实际上，任何技术趋势都在发展。
but just really anything that's trending in tech.
然后在YCombinator的网站上建立了一个名为Hacker News的网站
And then a website called Hacker News on YCombinator's site
那也是偶尔看一眼的地方
that also is a place to just glance at once in a while
因为您会看到最新和最好的库或其他内容
because you'll see the latest and greatest libraries or something
那是新生的。
that's quite nascent.
因此，如果总的来说，您只是想了解新功能
So if in general you just want to get a sense of what's new
以及科技界的趋势，事物
and what's trending out there in the tech world, things
即使你不在乎也应该意识到
that you should just be aware of even if you don't care
进入那些做这些事情的杂草，
to get into the weeds of doing those things hands on,
这些都是不错的网站，肯定还有其他网站。
these are all good sites and surely others out there as well.
然后，CS50当然拥有自己的在线社区，其中一些
And then, CS50, of course, has its own online community, some of which
你们中的一些人在高中甚至更早之前就已经参加了一段时间。
some of you have been part for some time, in high school or even prior.
请随时与我们保持联系，
Please feel free to keep in touch with us in some way,
或还一些东西给你的继任者
or give back a little something to your successors who
可能会沿着这条路线或其他路线走
might take this or another course down the road
并不仅在这里参与这些社区的提问，
and participate not only in asking questions in these communities here,
而且还要回答别人的问题。
but also in answering others' questions as well.
所以我们认为我们会少做一些讨论
So we thought we would do a little less of the talking
现在，一起扭转局面，共同进行最终的社区活动。
now and turn things around for a sort of final community activity together.
感谢许多提出问题的人
Thanks to many of you who have contributed questions
在过去的几周中。
over the past couple of weeks.
多亏了Brian，我们认为我们可以一起举办CS50测验节目
Thanks to Brian, we thought we'd put together a CS50 quiz show
在此结束最后的演讲。
on which to end this final lecture.
这些是您，员工，Brian提出的问题。
These are questions written by you, by the staff, by Brian.
这将是每个人嗡嗡作响的机会
And it'll be an opportunity for everyone to buzz in
他们对我们预先准备的大约20个问题的回答。
with their answers to some 20 questions that we have prepared in advance.
时间就是生命。
Time is of the essence.
因此，如果您加快蜂鸣速度，您的分数将会更高。
So your score will be higher if you buzz in more quickly.
因此，重要的是不仅要正确，
So it's important not only to be correct,
而且对于这个特定对象也要快速。
but also to be fast for this particular one as well.
稍后，我将继续分享我的屏幕。
And in just a moment, I'm going to go ahead and share my screen.
再说一次，我们这里有大约20个问题，所有问题都来自于
And, again, we'll have some 20 questions here, all of them drawn from,
受CS50启发的某种形式。
inspired by CS50 in some form.
在每个问题之后，根据有多少人是对是错，
And after each question, depending on how many people get it right or wrong,
我们将花一点时间至少说明它在哪里正确
we'll take a moment to at least explain where it is you went right
还是在哪里你错了。
or where it is you went wrong.
好吧，布莱恩。
All right, Brian.
准备好了吗？
Ready on your end?
布莱恩·于：我们已经准备好出发了。
BRIAN YU: We are ready to go.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：好吧，让我们继续看一下
DAVID MALAN: All right, well, let's go ahead and take a look
这里有第一个问题。
with the first question here.
将源代码编译为机器代码的步骤是什么？
What are the steps for compiling source code into machine code?
预处理，编译，组装和链接？
Preprocessing, compiling, assembling, and linking?
编写，编译，调试和测试？
Writing, compiling, debugging, and testing?
处理，创建，声明和叮当声？
Processing, creating, asserting, and clang?
还是赚？
Or make?
继续并在手机，笔记本电脑或台式机上嗡嗡作响，
Go ahead and buzz in on your phone or laptop or desktop,
使用与Brian提供的网址相同的网址。
using that same URL that Brian provided.
每个问题您有20秒的时间，现在剩下两个。
You've got 20 seconds for each question, two of which now remain.
时间到了。
That's it for time.
让我们继续来看一下这里的结果。
Let's go ahead and take a look at the results here.
你们当中有70％的人说要进行预处理，编译，组装，
It looks like 70% of you said preprocessing, compiling, assembling,
和链接。
and linking.
布莱恩，您想告诉我们是否正确吗？
Brian, would you like to tell us if that's right?
布莱恩·于：是的。
BRIAN YU: Yes.
这是正确的答案。
That is the correct answer.
首先进行预处理，然后进行编译，组装和链接
Preprocessing first, compiling, assembling, and linking, all of that
在幕后。
is behind the scenes.
因此，您不必每次编译时都考虑。
So you don't necessarily think about every time you compile.
但这确实是步骤。
But those are, indeed, the steps.
DAVID MALAN：公平地说，make可以说是一种抽象
DAVID MALAN: And to be fair, make is arguably an abstraction
因为这只是整个过程的开始。
for all of that insofar as it just kicks off the whole process.
但我认为，更准确地说，步骤的答案是，
But I think a little more precisely, an answer to steps would be,
确实，那四件事在那里。
indeed, those four things there.
好吧，让我们在这里看一下计分板。
All right, let's take a look at the scoreboard here.
我们有大量的来宾帐户。
We have a whole number of guest accounts.
第200位来宾处于领先地位，但在此与其他几位客人并列。
Guest number 200 is in the lead, but tied with several other guests here.
因此，那些拥有1,000分的人很快就会嗡嗡作响。
So those of you with 1,000 points buzzed in really quickly.
因此，时间再次至关重要。
So again time is of the essence.
下一个问题，二进制搜索的运行时间是多少？
Next question, what is the runtime of binary search?
它是1的O，log n的O，n的O，还是n的O的平方？
Is it O of 1, O of log n, O of n, or O of n squared?
剩下15秒，即二进制搜索的运行时间。
15 seconds remain, the runtime of binary search.
回想一下，这是我们研究的首批算法之一。
Recall, this was one of the first algorithms we looked at.
它最初带有电话簿，
It was first incarnated with a phone book,
即使我们并没有在很早以前就用这个名字来称呼它。
even if we didn't call it that by name early on.
布莱恩，让我们看一下结果。
Brian, let's take a look at the results.
看起来有61％的人说登录n。
Looks like 61% of you say log n.
布莱恩？
Brian?
布莱恩·于：答案n是正确的答案。
BRIAN YU: Log n is the correct answer.
如果您还记得那本电话簿，问题是
If you remember that phone book, the question
真的可以归结为多少次
really came down to how many times can we
一次又一次地将电话簿分开
divide that phone book and half again and again
一次又一次，直到我们只讨论一页。
and again, until we get down to just one page.
如果电话簿中有三页是n页，那么结果就是n的日志。
And that turns out to be log of n if three are n pages in the phone book.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：的确，随时随地都有一些技巧在向前发展
DAVID MALAN: Indeed, and sort of pro tip moving forward in life, any time
您会看到一半又一半又一半发生了一些事情，
you see something happening in half and half and half and half,
很有可能会涉及一种算法
odds are there's going to be an algorithm involved
在其分析中的某处。
somewhere in the analysis thereof.
好吧，这里的下一个排行榜，来宾200略有下降。
All right, next leaderboard here, guest 200 slipped down a little bit.
但是现在我们有一大堆人以2,000分排在第一位。
But we have a whole bunch of people tied in first place for 2,000 points now.
下一个问题，其中哪些动物是第一个
Next question, which of these animals was the first
在CS50讲座中提到？
to be mentioned in a CS50 lecture?
骆驼，蟒蛇，鸭，猫。
Llama, python, duck, cat.
剩下15秒。
15 seconds remain.
CS50讲座中首先提到的是哪个？
Which was mentioned first in a CS50 lecture?
让我们看看结果。
And let's see the results.
看起来猫只勉强接受了51％的鸭子。
Looks like cat just barely eked out duck with 51%.
布莱恩？
Brian?
布莱恩·于：实际上，猫是正确的答案。
BRIAN YU: And cat is, in fact, the correct answer.
骆驼出现在实验室1中，但在讲课中没有提及。
Llamas showed up in Lab 1, but they were not mentioned in lecture.
鸭子直到一点点才露面
The duck didn't show up until a little bit
稍后当我们谈论调试时。
later when we talked about debugging.
在讲座的最后简短地提到了Python。
And Python was briefly mentioned at the end of the lecture.
但这是在我们向Scratch介绍自己之后。
But it was after we introduced ourselves to Scratch.
而且，Scratch的主要角色当然是猫。
And the main character in Scratch is, of course, the cat.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：好的，我们可能很快就会在这里看到一些传播。
DAVID MALAN: All right, we're probably going to see a bit of spread here soon.
但是，我们有一整群人有3,000。
We have a whole bunch of people with 3,000, though.
但是名称开始有所不同。
But the names are starting to vary.
让我们继续下一个问题。
Let's move on to the next question.
每次分配内存时，还必须确保-
Every time you malloc memory, you must also be sure to--
重新分配，返回，释放还是退出？
realloc, return, free, or exit?
每次分配内存时，还应确保重新分配内存，
Every time you malloc memory, you should also be sure to realloc,
返回，免费还是退出？
return, free, or exit?
回想一下，malloc是许多分段错误的根源
Recall that malloc was the source of a lot of segmentation faults
学期中。
mid-semester.
现在有78％的受访者表示免费。
The responses now are 78% said free.
布莱恩，你同意吗？
Brian, do you concur?
布莱恩·于：他们都是正确的。
BRIAN YU: And they are all correct.
每当您分配内存时，请动态地向计算机请求一些内存。
Whenever you malloc memory, ask the computer for some memory dynamically.
完成后，应将其还给计算机
When you're done with it, you should give it back to the computer
通过免费拨打。
by calling free.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：确实，还有布莱恩（Brian），
DAVID MALAN: Indeed, and Brian, as a teachable
那一刻，为什么我们从来没有免费拨打过电话的got_string，我们现在
moment, why is it that we never had a call free forget_string, which we now
知道引擎盖下面正在使用某种东西
know underneath the hood is using something
像malloc分配内存？
like malloc to allocate memory?
布莱恩·于：所以get_string是CS50库中的一个函数。
BRIAN YU: So get_string was a function in CS50's library.
CS50的库将为您处理该内存管理过程。
And CS50's library takes care of that memory management process for you.
因此，您不必担心自己释放所有这些内存。
So you didn't have to worry about freeing all of that memory yourself.
DAVID MALAN：的确如此，但是任何时候调用malloc都必须免费。
DAVID MALAN: Indeed, but anytime you call malloc, you must call free.
好吧，这里的排行榜看起来像我们
All right, the leaderboard here looks like we have
来宾600仍然领先4,000。
guest 600 still in the lead with 4,000.
下一个问题。
Next question.
什么是比赛条件？
What is a race condition?
什么时候适合赛车比赛？
When conditions are nice out for racing?
当两件事同时发生并产生意想不到的结果时？
When two things happen at the same time and produce an unexpected result?
当一行代码执行得太快时？
When a line of code is executed too quickly?
当一行代码执行得太慢时？
When a line of code is executed too slowly?
什么是比赛条件？
What is a race condition?
啊，事情很快就升级了。
Ah, things just escalated quickly.
但是您会记得这是在SQL上下文中出现的。
But you'll recall this came up in the context of SQL.
和数据库，0秒，让我们看看。
And databases, 0 seconds, let's see.
85％的人说同时发生两件事
85% said when two things happen at the same time
并产生意想不到的结果。布莱恩？
and produce an unexpected result. Brian?
布莱恩·于：这是正确的答案。
BRIAN YU: That is the correct answer.
我赞赏至少有1％的人说，如果外面有条件
I appreciate that at least 1% of people said when conditions outside
非常适合赛车。
are nice for racing.
但是至少在计算机科学的背景下，
But in the context of computer science, at least,
当两件事同时发生并且可能产生意想不到的结果时，
when two things happen at the same time and could produce an unexpected result,
这就是我们所说的竞赛条件。
that is what we would refer to as a race condition.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：的确，回想起我和布莱恩的结局
DAVID MALAN: Indeed, recall that's how Brian and I ended up
冰箱里有太多牛奶。
with too much milk in the refrigerator.
因为我们都检查了该变量的状态
Because we both inspected the state of that variable
基本上是在同一时间。
at essentially the same time.
好吧，这里的排行榜。
All right, the leader board here.
现在，我们有一大群人获得了5,000分。
Now we have a whole bunch of people with 5,000 points.
让我们继续。
Let's move on.
放大照片是否可以增强照片以产生更多细节？
Does zooming in on a photo let you enhance it to generate more detail?
是的，就像CSI中一样。
Yes, just like in CSI.
不，一张照片只有一定数量的细节。
No, a photo only has a certain amount of detail.
放大照片是否可以增强照片以产生更多细节？
Does zooming in on a photo let you enhance it to generate more detail?
我会承认，我最近在看一些节目并想到了你
And I will admit, I was watching some show recently and thought of you
当他们从字面上说时，一切都会增强。
all when they literally said, enhance.
好的，0秒。
All right, 0 seconds.
似乎有93％的人说过，不，一张照片只有一定数量的细节。
Looks like 93% of you said, no, a photo only has a certain amount of detail.
你们中有7％的人说是，就像在CSI中一样。
7% of you said yes, just like in CSI.
布莱恩，您能帮助我们调和两者吗？
Brian, can you help us reconcile the two?
布莱恩·于：在这种情况下，93％是正确的。
BRIAN YU: The 93%, in this case, are correct.
一张照片只有一定数量的像素。
A photo only has a certain number of pixels.
如果您继续放大一个像素，
And if you keep zooming in on one pixel, you're
无法产生更多的细节，
not going to be able to generate additional detail that
以前不在那里。
wasn't there before.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：公平地说，这是一种变化。
DAVID MALAN: And to be fair, that's kind of sort of changing.
或者至少答案现在变得越来越难了
Or at least the answer is getting a little harder nowadays
借助机器学习或人工智能，
with machine learning or artificial intelligence,
算法在哪里弄清楚什么级别的细节
where algorithms sort of figure out what level of detail
可能或应该在那里。
could or should be there.
但这实际上只是统计推断，
But that really is just statistical inference,
实际上并没有恢复曾经存储的信息
that is not actually recovering information that was ever stored
在相机或其他设备上。
on the camera or some other device.
好吧，现在排行榜的得分是6,000分，这些人并列。
All right, the leaderboard now is at 6,000 points with these folks tied.
以下哪一项不是好的哈希函数的特征？
Which of the following is not a characteristic of a good hash function?
确定性输出，随机性，均匀分布，效率。
Deterministic output, randomness, uniform distribution, efficiency.
事情再次变得真实。
Things just got real again.
以下哪一项不是好的哈希函数的特征？
Which of the following is not a characteristic of a good hash function?
回想一下我们在哈希表的上下文中使用了哈希函数
Recall we used hash functions in the context of hash tables
在谈论数据结构时。
when talking about data structures.
好的？
All right?
一秒。
One second.
这次的答案更加广泛。
The answers are more spread this time.
62％的人不喜欢随机性。
62% don't like randomness.
布赖恩，应该吗？
Brian, should they?
布莱恩·于：那是正确的答案。
BRIAN YU: And that is the correct answer.
随机性不是良好哈希函数的特征。
Randomness is not a characteristic of a good hash function.
您希望您的哈希函数始终为您提供
You want your hash function to always give you
相同的输出给出相同的输入。
the same output given the same input.
这样，您可以依靠它的输出结果。
That way you can rely on whatever the output of it is.
如果是随机的，将很难使用。
If it's random, it's going to be hard to use.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：确实，请考虑使用拼写检查器
DAVID MALAN: Indeed, consider a spellchecker
随机说是或否。
that randomly says yes or no.
这是一个词，可能不是您想要的属性。
This is a word, probably not a property you want.
好吧，现在排行榜，我们正在努力达到7,000点，
All right, the leaderboard now, we're eking our way up to 7,000 points,
但终于开始看到一些传播。
but finally starting to see some spread.
因此，你们中的一些人还不够快或不够正确。
So a few of you haven't been quite quick or correct enough.
下一个问题，FIFO代表什么？
Next question, what does FIFO stand for?
先进先出
FIFO.
它是普通狗的名字吗，您的信用评分，先进先出，
Is it a common dog's name, your credit score, first in, first out,
功能输入，文件输出？
function input, file output?
FIFO代表什么？
What does FIFO stand for?
我会很好奇看到这里的蔓延。
I'll be curious to see the spread here.
让我们来看看。
Let's see.
你们中有80％说的是先进先出。
80% of you said first in, first out.
布莱恩？
Brian?
布莱恩·于：是的。
BRIAN YU: That is correct.
那就是我们用来形容的
And that was what we were using to describe
所谓的队列，队列中的第一件事
what would be called like a queue, where the first thing in the queue
是队列中的第一件事。
is the first thing that comes out of the queue.
因此，它遵循FIFO顺序。
So it obeys that FIFO ordering.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：的确，让我们在这里查看排行榜。
DAVID MALAN: Indeed, let's see the leaderboard here.
好吧，我们有大约8,000辆，但在7,000辆范围内还有更多。
All right, we have some 8,000s, but more in the 7,000 range.
接下来是一个更丰富多彩的问题。
Next up is a more colorful question.
以下哪一项将使用RGB值表示粉红色？
Which of the following would represent pink using RGB values?
我会让您自己阅读这些内容。
And I'll let you read these on your own.
当然，现在在幕后发生了一些谷歌搜索。
And surely, there's some Googling happening behind the scenes now.
但是没关系。
But that's OK.
实际上，谷歌非常聪明。
In fact, Google is pretty smart.
如果您输入一个十六进制代码，它甚至可能
If you type in a hexadecimal code, it might even
告诉您一些色轮或色板。
show you a little color wheel or swatch.
好吧，让我们看一下结果。
All right, let's take a look at the results.
似乎您中有55％的人说ffd0e0。
Looks like 55% of you said ffd0e0.
布莱恩？
Brian?
布莱恩·于：那是正确的。
BRIAN YU: And that is correct.
所以这些RGB值就像六个不同的值，
So those RGB values are like six different values,
其中每两个对应一种颜色，两个对应红色，两个对应绿色，
where each two correspond to one color, two for red, two for green,
两个为蓝色。
two for blue.
全部为十六进制。
This is all in hexadecimal.
而且粉红色每个都会很多。
And pink would be a lot of each of them.
因为它非常接近白色，就像
Because it's very close to white, which is, like,
全红，全绿，全蓝。
all red, all green, and all blue.
但是它比绿色和蓝色更红。
But it's more red than it is green and blue.
这样ffd0e0就是很多红色，绿色少了一点，
And so that one, ffd0e0, is a lot of red, a little bit less green,
少一点蓝色。
and a little bit less blue.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：的确如此。
DAVID MALAN: Indeed.
好吧，让我们看看我们在这里的位置。
All right, let's see where we're at here.
我们现在要做的-有趣。
We're now up to-- interesting.
没有人再有完美的分数了。
No one has a perfect score anymore.
但是，来宾200仍以9000点的微弱优势遥遥领先。
But guest 200 is still in the lead with just shy of 9,000 points.
在C中，以下哪几行代码分配
In C, which of the following lines of code allocates
足够的内存来存储字符串s的副本？
enough memory for a copy of the string s?
我会让你读这些。
I'll let you read these.
在C中，以下哪几行代码分配
In C, which of the following lines of code allocates
足够的内存来存储字符串s的副本？
enough memory for a copy of the string s?
似乎这里有很多可行的选择。
Bunch of viable choices here, it would seem.
时间，让我们看一下结果。
And time, let's take a look at the results.
看起来有46％的人说过大小为s的malloc。
Looks like 46% said malloc of size s.
但是33％的布莱恩说s的strlen的malloc加1。
But Brian, 33% said malloc of strlen of s plus 1.
谁是对的？
Who is right?
布莱恩·于：在这种情况下，少数族裔在这里是33％是正确的。
BRIAN YU: And in this case, the minority, the 33% are correct here.
记住，Malloc将内存的字节数作为其参数
Malloc, remember, takes as its argument the number of bytes of memory
您要分配的。
that you want to allocate.
如果您有一个字符串，并且想弄清楚需要多少个字节，
And if you have a string and you want to figure out how many bytes you need,
你需要知道的第一件事是弄清楚
first thing you need to know is figure out
那弦多久。很高兴会告诉你
how long is that string. strlen will tell you
该字符串中有多少个字符。
how many characters are in that string.
但是您确实需要一个额外的字节，因为在每个字符串的末尾，
But you do need one additional byte, because at the end of every string,
我们有一个空终止符。
we have that null terminating character.
为此，我们需要一个字节的内存。
And we need one byte of memory for that.
因此，str的slen将为您提供字符串的长度加1。
So strlen of s will give you the length of the string plus 1.
那就是您需要多少字节的内存。
That's how many bytes you need for memory.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：的确如此。
DAVID MALAN: Indeed.
瞧，您免费获得任何东西。
And see, you get nothing for free.
您想要做的任何事情都需要自己做。
Anything you want you need to do yourself.
实际上，加号1是您要解决的问题。
And indeed, the plus 1 is a problem for you to solve.
现在的发行，访客200仍然领先
The distribution now, guest 200 still in the lead with just
低于10,000点。
shy of 10,000 points.
那是问题10。
That was question 10.
我们在比赛的下半场。
We're in the second half of the game.
您应该如何整理衣服以保持凉爽？
How should you organize your clothes to be cool?
这是11号。
This is number 11.
堆栈，队列，字典，二叉树。
Stack, queue, dictionary, binary tree.
您应该如何整理衣服以保持凉爽？
How should you organize your clothes to be cool?
您可能还记得教过我们的杰克和娄。
You might recall Jack and Lou, who taught us this one.
剩下两秒钟。
Two seconds remain.
好像有48％的人说队列，Brian。
And it looks like 48% said queue, Brian.
布莱恩·于：那是正确的。
BRIAN YU: And that is correct.
因此，从与杰克和娄在一起的视频中
So from that video with Jack and Lou, there
是组织线索的不同方式。
were different ways of organizing the clues.
但是那段视频的结论是，你
But the conclusion of that video was, you
想把你的衣服排成一排。
want to put your clothes in a queue.
这样，在处理完一个之后，就将其放在队列的末尾。
So that after you're done with one, you put it at the end of the queue.
在返回到已经穿过的衣服之前，请先使用其他衣服。
And you use something else before you go back to the one you already wore.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：的确如此。
DAVID MALAN: Indeed.
好的。
All right.
现在排行榜上，来宾10打破了10,000。
And the leaderboard now, looks like guest 10 broke 10,000.
但是其他人也是如此。
But so did a bunch of other people.
下一个问题，什么是细分错误？
Next question, what is a segmentation fault?
当计算机内存不足时，当我们的程序尝试
When a computer runs out of memory, when our program tries
当程序尝试访问它的内存时读取空文件
to read an empty file, when a program tries to access memory that it
不应该，当地震发生时。
shouldn't, when an earthquake happens.
看起来其中许多可能都非常接近。
Looks like a lot of these could be pretty close.
两秒钟
Two seconds.
让我们看看。
And let's see.
看起来有80％的人说，当程序尝试访问内存时，不应这样做。
Looks like 80% said when a program tries to access memory that it shouldn't.
布莱恩？
Brian?
布莱恩·于：这是正确的答案。
BRIAN YU: That is the correct answer.
尝试时可能会发生细分错误
Segmentation fault can happen if you're trying
触摸您不应该访问程序内部的内存。
to touch memory that you're not supposed to have access to inside of a program.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：对于13％的人
DAVID MALAN: And for the 13% of people who
说，当计算机内存不足时，为什么这里不是答案？
said when a computer runs out of memory, why is that not quite the answer here?
布莱恩·于：这样计算机可能会耗尽内存。
BRIAN YU: So the computer could run out of memory.
当您调用malloc时，malloc可能会返回null，
Where when you call malloc, malloc might return null,
因为没有可用的内存来分配。
because there's no available memory to allocate.
但是只要您对此进行检查，并且我们会尽力鼓励您，
But as long as you check for that, and we try and encourage you,
每当您分配内存时，都要检查一下您是否返回了该值
whenever you're mallocing memory, to check to see if the value you get back
一片空白。
is null.
这可以帮助您避免这些类型的错误。
That can help you to avoid those types of errors.
戴维·马兰（DAVID MALAN）：现在让我们看一下董事会。
DAVID MALAN: So let's take a look at the board now.
11,000位客人200的东西。
11,000 something for guest 200.
现在让我们继续这个问题。
Let's now proceed with this question.
递归会导致以下哪种类型的溢出
Which of the following types of overflow can result from recursion
没有基本情况？
without a base case?
堆溢出，整数溢出，堆栈溢出，缓冲区溢出。
Heap overflow, integer overflow, stack overflow, buffer overflow.
确实出现了各种形式的溢出。
And all forms of overflow, indeed, came up.
当然，其中之一也是受欢迎的网站的名称。
One of them is also, of course, the name of a popular website.
但是所有这些都是实际的东西。
But all of these are actual things.
但是哪个是正确的？
But which is correct?
好吧，让我们看看结果。
All right, let's see the results.
看起来有61％，60％发生了堆栈溢出。
Looks like 61%, 60% went with stack overflow.
布莱恩？
Brian?
布莱恩·于：那是正确的。
BRIAN YU: And that is correct.
每次调用函数时，您最终都会获得一点内存
Every time you call a function, you end up getting a little bit of memory
在该功能的堆栈上。
on the stack for that function.
而且，如果您一遍又一遍地递归地调用该函数
And if you keep calling that function recursively over and over
永不停止，因为没有基本情况，
and never stop, because there's no base case,
那么您可能会耗尽堆栈空间。
then you can run out of stack space.
我们称之为堆栈溢出。
And we call that a stack overflow.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：的确如此。
DAVID MALAN: Indeed.
好吧，让我们现在来看排行榜。
All right, let's see the leaderboard now.
来宾200人，仍然是要击败的人。
Guest 200, still the one to beat.
但是来宾216并不太落后。
But guest 216 is not too far behind.
下一个问题。
Next question.
在Fiftyville镇，名字叫什么
In the town of Fiftyville, what were the names
目睹橡皮鸭抢劫案的三个人中有谁？
of the three people who witnessed the rubber duck robbery?
我会让你读这些。
I'll let you read these.
在Fiftyville镇，这三个人的名字是什么
In the town of Fiftyville, what were the names of the three people
目睹了橡皮鸭抢劫案。
who witnessed the rubber duck robbery.
今年出现了一个新问题，回想起他完全从IDE中消失了
A new problem this year, recall that he disappeared altogether from the IDE
那个星期。
for that week.
好吧，让我们看看结果。
All right, let's see the results.
布莱恩，这个很近。
Brian, this one is close.
33％的人说露丝，尤金和雷蒙德。
33% said Ruth, Eugene, and Raymond.
布莱恩·于：露丝，尤金和雷蒙德是正确的。
BRIAN YU: And Ruth, Eugene, and Raymond is correct.
他们得到的回应比其他任何人都多。
They've got more responses than any of the others.
这很棘手。
It was tricky.
但是，是的，这是正确的答案。
But yeah, that's the correct answer.
名称背后没有太多理由。
There wasn't a whole lot of reason behind the names.
我对这个故事本身做了很多思考。
I put a lot of thought into the story itself.
但是对名称并没有太多的想法。
But not a lot of thought to the names.
这些只是随机选择的。
Those were kind of just randomly selected.
但这只是证人的名字。
But those were the names of the witnesses.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：的确如此。
DAVID MALAN: Indeed.
而现在的排行榜上，我们还有200位来宾被击败。
And the leaderboard now, we still have guest 200 is the one to beat.
这是问题15。
This is question 15.
因此，我们快结束了，仍然有机会继续前进。
So we are nearing the end, still chance to pull ahead.
以下哪个命令行程序检查您的代码是否存在内存泄漏？
Which of these command line programs checks your code for memory leaks?
Valgrind，clang，mkdir，make。
Valgrind, clang, mkdir, make.
请注意，这些都没有50，这意味着它们都是真实世界
Notice that none of these have 50 on it, which means these are all real world
您将继续在自己的Mac或PC上看到的命令
commands that you would continue to see on your own Mac or PC
或某些将来的Linux系统。
or some future Linux system.
让我们看看结果。
And let's see the results.
在这里，瓦尔格朗德是最明显的赢家，占78％。
Here we have valgrind, the clear winner, 78%.
布莱恩？
Brian?
布莱恩·于：那是正确的答案。
BRIAN YU: And that's the correct answer.
那是您可以用来检查程序的程序
That's the program you can use in order to check your program
看看是否有内存泄漏，看看
to see if you have any memory leaks, to see
如果您要触摸内存，那您就不应该，如果您忘记释放某些东西。
if you're touching memory you shouldn't, if you're forgetting to free something.
Valgrind对于所有这些都很有用。
Valgrind is useful for all of that.
戴维·马兰（DAVID MALAN）：如果可以的话，我觉得你们中有5％的人现在正与我们混为一谈。
DAVID MALAN: And if I may, I feel like 5% of you are just messing with us now.
希望如此，但我们会看到的。
Hopefully, but we shall see.
好的，最后五个问题。
All right, last five questions to go.
现在查看排行榜之后，访客200仍然位于顶部。
After taking a look at the leaderboard now, guest 200's still up at the top.
以下哪项在C中存在，但在Python中不存在。
Which of the following exists in C, but not Python.
布尔表达式，do-while循环，递归
Boolean expressions, do-while loops, recursive
函数，浮点数。
functions, floating-point numbers.
C中存在以下哪项，但Python中不存在？
Which of the following exists in C, but not Python?
两种语言之间有趣的比较，超出了语法。
An interesting comparison between two languages that goes beyond syntax.
好的。
All right.
时间到。
Time's up.
让我们来看看。
Let's take a look.
看起来68％的用户使用了do-while循环。
Looks like 68% went with do-while loops.
布莱恩？
Brian?
布莱恩·于：是的。
BRIAN YU: That is correct.
Python具有for循环。
Python has for loops.
Python具有while循环。
Python has while loops.
但是它没有C所具有的do-while循环。
But it doesn't have do-while loops in the same way that C does.
您必须找到其他方法来尝试实现
You'd have to find some other way of trying to achieve
同样的逻辑想法。
that same kind of logical idea.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：的确如此。
DAVID MALAN: Indeed.
布赖恩，当我们
And Brian, what was the approach that we took when we
试图在几周前重新创建？
tried to recreate that some weeks ago?
布莱恩·于：是的。
BRIAN YU: Yeah.
因此，一种解决方法是无限循环，尽管如此，
So one approach to it is having an infinite loop, while true,
这只会一直重复。
that will just always repeat.
然后，当您到达可以退出循环的位置时，
And then when you reach a point where you can exit the loop,
您可以使用命令中断来跳出循环
you can use the command break to get out of the loop
并继续执行该程序的其余部分。
and move on to the rest of the program.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：的确如此。
DAVID MALAN: Indeed.
好吧，让我们看一下董事会。
All right, let's take a look at the board.
来宾200仍为15938，但仍落后几个亲密朋友。
Guest 200 still now at 15,938, but still a few close folks behind.
发送私人信息时应使用哪种HTTP请求方法
What HTTP request method should you use when sending private information
像密码一样？
like a password?
GET，POST，SELECT还是TEXT？
GET, POST, SELECT, or TEXT?
发送时应使用哪种HTTP请求方法
Which HTTP request method should use when sending
私人信息（例如密码）？
private information like a password?
看一下结果。
Take a look at the results.
好的。
All right.
POST的发布者很多，Brian，74％
And the distribution is a lot of people said POST, Brian, 74%
布莱恩·于：他们是正确的。
BRIAN YU: And they are correct.
是的，如果这是一个获取请求，那么您最终会
Yeah, if it was a get request, then you would end up
网址中可能包含敏感信息
with sensitive information inside the URL that might show up
例如，在您的浏览历史记录中。
in your browsing history, for example.
为了安全起见，您需要确保使用POST请求
So to be secure, you want to be sure to use the POST request
这种类型的东西的方法。
method for that type of stuff.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：明确一点，请不要这样做。
DAVID MALAN: And to be clear, don't do this.
获取是可能的，我们看到了如何做到这一点。
Get is possible, and we saw how to do that.
但是，当然那会在您的历史记录和其他暴露的地方结束。
But of course, that then ends up in your history and other exposed places.
SELECT和TEXT不是HTTP动词。
SELECT and TEXT were not HTTP verbs.
因此POST确实可以实现。
So POST is indeed spot on.
好的，只剩下三个问题。
All right, only three questions remain.
来宾200仍然是被击败的人，其次是来宾216。
Guest 200 is still the one to beat, followed by guest 216.
什么数据结构允许恒定时间查找字典中的单词？
What data structure allows for constant time look up for words in a dictionary?
链表，二进制搜索树，数组还是特里？
A linked list, a binary search tree, an array, or a trie?
回想一下字典是一个抽象数据
Recall that a dictionary was an abstract data
类型，只要您可以以不同的方式实现它即可。
type, insofar as you could implement it in different ways.
但是要获取恒定的时间，您可能需要
But to get constant time look up, you might want
在其中之一上使用其中之一。
to use one of these over the others.
让我们看看结果。
Let's see the results.
有趣的。
Interesting.
布赖恩，有32％的人说特里。
Brian, 32% said trie.
您能在这里帮助我们吗？
Can you help us out here?
布莱恩·于：是的。
BRIAN YU: Yeah.
特里是正确的答案。
The trie is the correct answer.
对于其他所有链接列表，二进制搜索树和数组，
For all of the others, the linked list, the binary search tree, and the array,
随着字典中越来越多的单词，
as you have more and more words in the dictionary,
找到一个单词将花费越来越长的时间，
it's going to take longer and longer to find a word,
因为您必须通过它进行线性搜索
as you have to either linear search through it
否则您必须遍历二叉搜索树中的各个节点。
or you have to go down through various nodes in the binary search tree.
另一方面，特里仅取决于单词的长度
The trie on the other hand, it only depends upon the length of the word
您正在查找。
that you're looking up.
词典中有多少个单词都没有关系。
It doesn't matter how many words are in the dictionary.
您只需在要查找的单词中的每个字母后面跟随一个节点。
You just follow one node for each letter in the word you're looking up.
而且您会在恒定时间内找到该单词。
And you'll find that word in constant time.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：布赖恩（Brian），如果持续时间不变，那么1的大O值是如此之好，
DAVID MALAN: And Brian, if constant time, Big O of 1 is so good,
那么，为什么不对所有内容都使用尝试呢？
why not use tries, then, for everything?
布莱恩·于：嗯，一切都有取舍。
BRIAN YU: Well, there are trade offs for everything.
尝试可为您提供理论上恒定的时间。
The trie gives you theoretically constant time.
但是最大的折衷之一是记忆力。
But one of the big trade offs is memory.
尝试最终使用更多的内存来
That tries end up using much more memory to be
能够比许多其他数据结构存储字典。
able to store a dictionary than many of those other data structures would.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：的确如此。
DAVID MALAN: Indeed.
让我们看一下结果。
Let's look at the results.
和来宾200仍然处于领先地位。
And guest 200 still at the lead.
但是，来宾752现在正踩在他们的脚跟上。
But guest 752 is now nipping at their heels.
最后两个问题。
We have two final questions.
速度又很重要。
And speed, again, does matter.
什么是Cookie？
What is a cookie?
用于在网站上识别您的计算机的数据，美味小吃，
Data used to identify your computer to websites, a delicious snack,
以上两种情况，或以上两种都不存在。
both of the above, or none of the above.
布赖恩，这是一个艰难的过程。
This is a tough one, Brian.
特别是在只有一个正确答案的情况下。
Especially if there's only one right answer.
我们可能会看到更多分歧。
We might see a bit more of a split.
其中哪一个是Cookie？
Which of these is a cookie?
好吧，让我们看看结果。
All right, let's see the results.
用于识别您的计算机的数据占网站总数的60％。
Data used to identify your computer to websites with 60%.
以上两者均为35％。
Both of the above was 35%.
你们中只有2％的人喜欢饼干。
Only 2% of you like cookies alone.
布莱恩？
Brian?
布莱恩·于：上面的两个都是正确的答案。
BRIAN YU: Both of the above was the correct answer.
我要提醒的是，所有这些问题都是由学生最初写的
I'll remind that all of these questions were written originally by students
被选为正确答案的学生的答案选择是
and the answer choice of students selected as the correct one was
以上两者。
both of the above.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: All right.
而现在倒数第二的排行榜，Guest 200仍然处于领先地位。
And now the second to last leaderboard, Guest 200 is still in the lead.
但是底部有一些差异。
But there's been some variance toward the bottom there.
CS50本身的最后一个问题。
Very last question of CS50 itself.
您现在的舒适水平是多少？
What's your comfort level now?
我们也将让您在这些答案中做出决定。
And we'll let you decide among these answers, too.
好的。
All right.
答案全在。
Answers are all in.
让我们看一下分布。
Let's take a look at the distribution.
似乎有43％的人说您更自在。
Looks like 43% of you said you're among more of those more comfortable.
你们中有24％的人选择了第二名。
24% of you went with the second.
19％，从上到下的分布非常引人入胜。
19%, very fascinating distribution from top to bottom.
但关键是，您现在的确已正式入职
But the point is that you are all indeed now officially inducted
进入那些更舒适的地方。
into those more comfortable.
非常感谢您加入CS50。
Thank you so much for joining us in CS50.
我们迫不及待想看到您的最终项目。
We cannot wait to see your final projects.
到此，这就是结局。
This, then, is the end.
这就是CS50。
And this was CS50.
[音乐播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]